<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>4thWave AI — Nanotech (Aggregated)</title>
    <link>https://www.4thwaveai.com</link>
    <description>Aggregated feed generated by 4thWave AI.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:35:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-thin sodium films offer low-cost alternative to gold and silver in optical technologies</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ultra-thin-sodium-alternative-gold.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ultra-thin-sodium-alternative-gold.html</guid>
      <description>From solar panels to next-generation medical devices, many emerging technologies rely on materials that can manipulate light with extreme precision. These materials—called plasmonic materials—are typically made from expensive metals like gold or silver. But what if a cheaper, more abundant metal could do the job just as well or better?</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/shining-a-new-light-on-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicists maneuver DNA molecules using electrical fields, offering real-time control</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-physicists-maneuver-dna-molecules-electrical.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-physicists-maneuver-dna-molecules-electrical.html</guid>
      <description>Researchers in McGill&#x27;s Department of Physics have developed a new device that can trap and study DNA molecules without touching or damaging them. The device, which uses carefully tuned electric fields, offers scientists unprecedented control over how DNA behaves in real time, creating the opportunity for faster, more precise molecular analysis that could improve diagnostics, genome mapping and the study of disease-related molecules.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/physicists-maneuver-dn-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Researchers develop fat-like nanoparticles to treat fatty liver disease</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-fat-nanoparticles-fatty-liver-disease.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-fat-nanoparticles-fatty-liver-disease.html</guid>
      <description>Researchers from the Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore (NUS Medicine), have developed a novel RNA-based therapy that could transform treatment for metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis (MASH), previously known as non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD), which affects approximately 25% of people worldwide, and up to 40% of adults in Singapore.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/researchers-develop-fa-3.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floquet Chern insulators based on nonlinear photonic crystals achieved</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-floquet-chern-insulators-based-nonlinear.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-floquet-chern-insulators-based-nonlinear.html</guid>
      <description>Over the past few years, engineers and material scientists have been trying to devise new optical systems in which light particles (i.e., photons) can move freely and in useful ways, irrespective of defects and imperfections. Topological phases, unique states of matter that are not defined by local properties, but by non-local and global features, can enable the robust movement of photons despite material defects.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/the-realization-of-flo.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-generated nanomaterial images fool even experts, study shows</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ai-generated-nanomaterial-images-experts.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ai-generated-nanomaterial-images-experts.html</guid>
      <description>Black-and-white images of pom-pom–like clusters, semi-translucent fields of tiny dark gray stars on a pale background, and countless other abstract patterns are a familiar sight in scientific papers describing the shapes and properties of newly engineered materials.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/ai-fakes-are-so-good-e-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver-nanoring coating points to &#x27;self-regulating&#x27; smart windows—without power or tinting</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-silver-nanoring-coating-smart-windows.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-silver-nanoring-coating-smart-windows.html</guid>
      <description>A new Danish research breakthrough could make buildings far more energy-efficient in the future. Researchers from Aarhus University&#x27;s Interdisciplinary Nanoscience Center (iNANO) have developed a light-responsive hybrid material based on so-called silver nanorings that automatically responds to solar intensity and regulates how much heat penetrates through windows.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/passive-silver-nanorin.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/video/2025/passive-silver-nanorin.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing random nanofiber networks, optimized for strength and toughness</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-random-nanofiber-networks-optimized-strength.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-random-nanofiber-networks-optimized-strength.html</guid>
      <description>In nature, random fiber networks such as some of the tissues in the human body, are strong and tough with the ability to hold together but also stretch a lot before they fail. Studying this structural randomness—that nature seems to replicate so effortlessly—is extremely difficult in the lab and is even more difficult to accurately reproduce in engineering applications.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/designing-random-fiber-2.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#x27;Nanoreactor&#x27; cage uses visible light for catalytic and ultra-selective cross-cycloadditions</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-nanoreactor-cage-visible-catalytic-ultra.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-nanoreactor-cage-visible-catalytic-ultra.html</guid>
      <description>Researchers have engineered a novel M6L4 octahedral molecular cage by integrating photoactive cyclometalated platinum(II) units, creating a visible-light-responsive &quot;nanoreactor&quot; that drives highly efficient photochemical reactions through precise molecular confinement. This innovative design overcomes the limitations of previous hosts, achieving perfect stereo- and site-selective cross-[2 + 2] cycloaddition reactions, and most notably, enabling catalytic cross-[2 + 2] cycloaddition of chemically inert substrates using this supramolecular confinement approach.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/nanoreactor-cage-uses.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat-rechargeable design powers nanoscale molecular machines</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-rechargeable-powers-nanoscale-molecular-machines.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-rechargeable-powers-nanoscale-molecular-machines.html</guid>
      <description>Though it might seem like science fiction, scientists are working to build nanoscale molecular machines that can be designed for myriad applications, such as &quot;smart&quot; medicines and materials. But like all machines, these tiny devices need a source of power, the way electronic appliances use electricity or living cells use ATP (adenosine triphosphate, the universal biological energy source).</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/heat-rechargeable-desi.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser pulses in graphene control electrons with lightning speed and nanometer precision</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-laser-pulses-graphene-electrons-lightning.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-laser-pulses-graphene-electrons-lightning.html</guid>
      <description>A research team in Kiel has demonstrated a previously unknown effect in graphene—a single layer of carbon atoms whose discovery earned the 2010 Nobel Prize. For years, graphene has been seen as a promising material for nanoelectronics, thanks to its exceptional conductivity, flexibility, and stability. Now, researchers from the Institute of Theoretical Physics and Astrophysics at Kiel University have taken this promise a step further.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/graphene-steers-electr.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists see shape memory activation in &#x27;smart&#x27; plastic</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-memory-smart-plastic.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-memory-smart-plastic.html</guid>
      <description>Researchers from the Skoltech Engineering Center&#x27;s Hierarchically Structured Materials Laboratory, in collaboration with colleagues from MISIS University and the Joint Institute for Nuclear Research, have for the first time observed nanoscale transformations in ultra-high molecular weight polyethylene—a material possessing a shape memory effect—in real time.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/scientists-see-shape-m.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny nanoparticles conquer the big three in polymer glasses: Strength, toughness and processability</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-tiny-nanoparticles-conquer-big-polymer.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-tiny-nanoparticles-conquer-big-polymer.html</guid>
      <description>Scientists have found a nanoparticle-inspired solution to the age-old strength issue of polymer glasses. Seasoning the polymer glass recipe with single-chain nanoparticles, which are tiny, folded-up polymer strands, can make the glass stronger, tougher, and easier to process by acting as reinforcements.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/2025/tiny-nanoparticles-con-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This ultra-thin solar tech could power everything from phones to skyscrapers</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/10/251001092218.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/10/251001092218.htm</guid>
      <description>A team in Sweden has unraveled the hidden structure of a promising solar material using machine learning and advanced simulations. Their findings could unlock durable, ultra-efficient solar cells for a rapidly electrifying world.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/formamidinium-lead-iodide.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The hidden forces inside diamonds that could make tech 1,000x faster</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250929055000.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250929055000.htm</guid>
      <description>A team of physicists has discovered that virtual charges, which exist only during brief interactions with light, play a critical role in ultrafast material responses. Using attosecond pulses on diamonds, they showed these hidden carriers significantly influence optical behavior. The findings could accelerate the development of petahertz-speed devices, unlocking a new era of ultrafast electronics.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/futuristic-energy-particles-ultrafast-electronics.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toxic waste could become the next clean energy breakthrough</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250926035016.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250926035016.htm</guid>
      <description>Bio-tar, once seen as a toxic waste, can be transformed into bio-carbon with applications in clean energy and environmental protection. This innovation could reduce emissions, create profits, and solve a major bioenergy industry problem.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/liquid-oil-petroleum.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny new lenses, smaller than a hair, could transform phone and drone cameras</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250921090853.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250921090853.htm</guid>
      <description>Scientists have developed a new multi-layered metalens design that could revolutionize portable optics in devices like phones, drones, and satellites. By stacking metamaterial layers instead of relying on a single one, the team overcame fundamental limits in focusing multiple wavelengths of light. Their algorithm-driven approach produced intricate nanostructures shaped like clovers, propellers, and squares, enabling improved performance, scalability, and polarization independence.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/metamaterial-lenses-for-phones-and-drones.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists just made atoms talk to each other inside silicon chips</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250920214318.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250920214318.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers at UNSW have found a way to make atomic nuclei communicate through electrons, allowing them to achieve entanglement at scales used in today’s computer chips. This breakthrough brings scalable, silicon-based quantum computing much closer to reality.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/two-nuclear-spins-remotely-entangled.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New cooling breakthrough nearly doubles efficiency</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250919085242.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250919085242.htm</guid>
      <description>CHESS thin-film materials nearly double refrigeration efficiency compared to traditional methods. Scalable and versatile, they promise applications from household cooling to space exploration.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/chess-efficient-thermoelectric-cooling-device.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lasers just made atoms dance, unlocking the future of electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250917221007.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250917221007.htm</guid>
      <description>Scientists at Michigan State University have discovered how to use ultrafast lasers to wiggle atoms in exotic materials, temporarily altering their electronic behavior. By combining cutting-edge microscopes with quantum simulations, they created a nanoscale switch that could revolutionize smartphones, laptops, and even future quantum computers.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/lasers-atomic-motion.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harvard’s salt trick could turn billions of tons of hair into eco-friendly materials</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250916221913.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250916221913.htm</guid>
      <description>Scientists at Harvard have discovered how salts like lithium bromide break down tough proteins such as keratin—not by attacking the proteins directly, but by altering the surrounding water structure. This breakthrough opens the door to a cleaner, more sustainable way to recycle wool, feathers, and hair into valuable materials, potentially replacing plastics and fueling new industries.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/protein-denaturation.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny magnetic spirals unlock the future of spintronics</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250913232933.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250913232933.htm</guid>
      <description>Scientists in Korea have engineered magnetic nanohelices that can control electron spin with extraordinary precision at room temperature. By combining structural chirality and magnetism, these nanoscale helices can filter spins without complex circuitry or cooling. The breakthrough not only demonstrates a way to program handedness in inorganic nanomaterials but also opens the door to scalable, energy-efficient spintronic devices that could revolutionize computing.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/electrosynthesized-chiral-ferromagnetic-nanohelix.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists just built a detector that could finally catch dark matter</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm</guid>
      <description>Physicists have unveiled a new superconducting detector sensitive enough to hunt dark matter particles smaller than electrons. By capturing faint photon signals, the device pushes the search into uncharted territory.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/superconducting-nanowire-single-photon-detector.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The invisible plastic threat you can finally see</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers in Germany and Australia have created a simple but powerful tool to detect nanoplastics—tiny, invisible particles that can slip through skin and even the blood-brain barrier. Using an &amp;quot;optical sieve&amp;quot; test strip viewed under a regular microscope, these particles reveal themselves through striking color changes.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/optical-sieve-nanoplastic-particles.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny gold quantum needles with astonishing powers discovered</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm</guid>
      <description>Scientists at the University of Tokyo have unveiled “gold quantum needles,” a newly discovered nanocluster structure formed under unusual synthesis conditions. Unlike typical spherical clusters, these elongated, pencil-shaped formations display unique quantum behaviors and respond to near-infrared light, making them promising tools for biomedical imaging and energy applications.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/structural-evolution-of-gold-nanoclusters.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>nanotech</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>