<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — All Areas (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://4thwave.ai"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:all</id>
  <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:35:14 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Qwen3 and DeepSeek-V3.1 models now available fully managed on AWS</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/aws/alibaba-qwen3-deepseek-v3-amazon-bedrock"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/aws/alibaba-qwen3-deepseek-v3-amazon-bedrock</id>
    <summary type="text">AWS continues to invest in being the best place to run open weight models with five new options that enhance model choice in Amazon Bedrock to further meet customers’ needs.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:03:23 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The UK’s ‘Goldilocks Moment for AI’: NVIDIA, UK and US Leaders Highlight AI Infrastructure Investments</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-ai-ecosystem-celebration/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-ai-ecosystem-celebration/</id>
    <summary type="text">NVIDIA founder and CEO Jensen Huang discussed the UK’s plans to become an AI superpower with UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer, UK Secretary of State for Science, Innovation and Technology Liz Kendall, UK Secretary of State for Business and Trade Peter Kyle, and US Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:21:03 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Kaggle Grandmasters Playbook: 7 Battle-Tested Modeling Techniques for Tabular Data | NVIDIA Technical Blog</title>
    <link href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/the-kaggle-grandmasters-playbook-7-battle-tested-modeling-techniques-for-tabular-data/"/>
    <id>https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/the-kaggle-grandmasters-playbook-7-battle-tested-modeling-techniques-for-tabular-data/</id>
    <summary type="text">Over hundreds of Kaggle competitions, we’ve refined a playbook that consistently lands us near the top of the leaderboard—no matter if we’re working with millions of rows, missing values…</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:29:36 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA Blackwell: Born for Extreme-Scale AI Inference</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/blackwell-ai-inference/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/blackwell-ai-inference/</id>
    <summary type="text">NVIDIA Blackwell is the core of a system architecture designed to power AI factories that produce intelligence through inference.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:00:25 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Inside the world’s most powerful AI datacenter - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/18/inside-the-worlds-most-powerful-ai-datacenter/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/18/inside-the-worlds-most-powerful-ai-datacenter/</id>
    <summary type="text">This week we have introduced a wave of purpose-built datacenters and infrastructure investments we are making around the world to support the global adoption of cutting-edge AI workloads and cloud services. Today in Wisconsin we introduced Fairwater, our newest US AI datacenter, the largest and most sophisticated AI factory we’ve built yet. In addition to...</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:00:02 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Independent sellers move 5 billion products annually through Amazon’s network of global logistics, domestic freight, and bulk warehousing</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/small-business/selling-on-amazon-supply-chain-explain"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/small-business/selling-on-amazon-supply-chain-explain</id>
    <summary type="text">Amazon launches new AI customs tools and expands its fulfillment offerings for Walmart, Shopify, and SHEIN, helping sellers simplify their supply chain and better serve customers across their channels</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:00:24 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amazon unveils new AI-powered tools to help sellers launch more winning products with greater speed</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation-at-amazon/amazon-ai-tools-sellers-product-launch"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation-at-amazon/amazon-ai-tools-sellers-product-launch</id>
    <summary type="text">New innovations give sellers unique insights to help them build sought-after products, reduce launch costs, and improve discoverability and conversion to drive new selection success.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:00:18 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bringing New tools To Help Businesses Boost Engagement, Customer Support and Discoverability</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/bringing-new-tools-to-help-businesses-boost-engagement-customer-support-and-discoverability/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/bringing-new-tools-to-help-businesses-boost-engagement-customer-support-and-discoverability/</id>
    <summary type="text">We hosted our second business summit in India where we showcased tools and features that will empower businesses of all sizes in establishing their presence, building better and delightful customer experiences, and growing their businesses.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:00:27 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meta Ray-Ban Display: AI Glasses With an EMG Wristband</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/meta-ray-ban-display-ai-glasses-emg-wristband/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/meta-ray-ban-display-ai-glasses-emg-wristband/</id>
    <summary type="text">Today at Connect, Mark Zuckerberg unveiled the next evolution in AI glasses: Meta Ray-Ban Display and Meta Neural Band.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:20:17 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Athletic Intelligence Is Here, Meet Oakley Meta Vanguard</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/oakley-meta-vanguard-performance-ai-glasses-sports/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/oakley-meta-vanguard-performance-ai-glasses-sports/</id>
    <summary type="text">Today at Connect, Mark Zuckerberg introduced Oakley Meta Vanguard, a brand-new line of Performance AI glasses built for high-intensity sports.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:14:06 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ray-Ban Meta (Gen 2) Now With Up to 2X the Battery Life and Better Video Capture</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/ray-ban-meta-gen-2-better-battery-life-video-capture/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/ray-ban-meta-gen-2-better-battery-life-video-capture/</id>
    <summary type="text">We’re introducing Ray-Ban Meta (Gen 2), the same stylish AI glasses you love with, now with new features.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:07:43 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Teaching Through the Latest Industrial Revolution  - EdSurge News</title>
    <link href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-18-teaching-through-the-latest-industrial-revolution"/>
    <id>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-18-teaching-through-the-latest-industrial-revolution</id>
    <summary type="text">The following story is part of our research series, Teaching Tech. To read more about this project, click here. Almost three years into the ChatGPT ...</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Introduction to Speculative Decoding for Reducing Latency in AI Inference | NVIDIA Technical Blog</title>
    <link href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/an-introduction-to-speculative-decoding-for-reducing-latency-in-ai-inference/"/>
    <id>https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/an-introduction-to-speculative-decoding-for-reducing-latency-in-ai-inference/</id>
    <summary type="text">Generating text with large language models (LLMs) often involves running into a fundamental bottleneck. GPUs offer massive compute, yet much of that power sits idle because autoregressive generation…</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:09:12 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amazon&#x27;s water conservation and replenishment efforts around the world</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/sustainability/amazon-water-conservation-replenishment-sustainability"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/sustainability/amazon-water-conservation-replenishment-sustainability</id>
    <summary type="text">Get the latest updates on how we’re reducing our water footprint and investing in innovations to address water scarcity.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:07:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to watch ‘Maintenance Required,’ coming soon to Prime Video</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/entertainment/maintenance-required-movie-prime-video"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/entertainment/maintenance-required-movie-prime-video</id>
    <summary type="text">Check out the trailer for the Lacey Uhlemeyer romantic comedy where a business owner confides in the very man behind her troubles.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:00:04 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What I Learned After Building a Tech Tool to Support Student Well-Being - EdSurge News</title>
    <link href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-17-what-i-learned-after-building-a-tech-tool-to-support-student-well-being"/>
    <id>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-17-what-i-learned-after-building-a-tech-tool-to-support-student-well-being</id>
    <summary type="text">This story was published by a Voices of Change fellow. Learn more about the fellowship here.One morning, my computer science students opened their ...</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The AI Makers: NVIDIA Partners in UK Advance Physical and Agentic AI, Robotics, Life Sciences and More</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-partner-ecosystem-ai-makers/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-partner-ecosystem-ai-makers/</id>
    <summary type="text">During NVIDIA founder and CEO Jensen Huang’s visit to the U.K. this week, NVIDIA highlighted how it is working with a broad ecosystem of AI makers across the nation on applications in physical and agentic AI, robotics and healthcare.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:30:16 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Microsoft leads shift beyond data unification to organization, delivering next-gen AI readiness with new Microsoft Fabric capabilities - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/16/microsoft-leads-shift-beyond-data-unification-to-organization-delivering-next-gen-ai-readiness-with-new-microsoft-fabric-capabilities/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/16/microsoft-leads-shift-beyond-data-unification-to-organization-delivering-next-gen-ai-readiness-with-new-microsoft-fabric-capabilities/</id>
    <summary type="text">We’re in a hinge moment for AI. The experiments are over and the real work has begun. Centralizing data, once the finish line, is now the starting point. The definition of “AI readiness” is evolving as increasingly sophisticated agents demand rich, contextualized data grounded in business operations to deliver meaningful results. What sets leaders apart...</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:00:04 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Teachers Turn Toward Virtual Schools for Better Work-Life Balance 
 - EdSurge News</title>
    <link href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-16-teachers-turn-toward-virtual-schools-for-better-work-life-balance"/>
    <id>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-16-teachers-turn-toward-virtual-schools-for-better-work-life-balance</id>
    <summary type="text">More teachers are flocking to virtual schools, citing better work-life balance, improved safety and more time for creativity as driving forces.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Build a Report Generator AI Agent with NVIDIA Nemotron on OpenRouter | NVIDIA Technical Blog</title>
    <link href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/build-a-report-generator-ai-agent-with-nvidia-nemotron-on-openrouter/"/>
    <id>https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/build-a-report-generator-ai-agent-with-nvidia-nemotron-on-openrouter/</id>
    <summary type="text">Unlike traditional systems that follow predefined paths, AI agents are autonomous systems that use large language models (LLMs) to make decisions, adapt to changing requirements…</summary>
    <updated>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:31:45 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How Much Freedom Do Teachers Have in the Classroom? In 2025, It’s Complicated. - EdSurge News</title>
    <link href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-15-how-much-freedom-do-teachers-have-in-the-classroom-in-2025-it-s-complicated"/>
    <id>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-15-how-much-freedom-do-teachers-have-in-the-classroom-in-2025-it-s-complicated</id>
    <summary type="text">PEN America this year identified more than a dozen states that have considered laws prohibiting teachers from displaying flags or signs related to ...</summary>
    <updated>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How Schools Are Helping Students Feel Safe Enough to Attend Amid Immigration Raids - EdSurge News</title>
    <link href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-12-how-schools-are-helping-students-feel-safe-enough-to-attend-class-amid-immigration-raids"/>
    <id>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-12-how-schools-are-helping-students-feel-safe-enough-to-attend-class-amid-immigration-raids</id>
    <summary type="text">“What they see are their classmates, their family members, their neighbors often being apprehended in violent and confusing ways, and this for children ...</summary>
    <updated>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A joint statement from Microsoft and OpenAI - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/11/a-joint-statement-from-microsoft-and-openai/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/11/a-joint-statement-from-microsoft-and-openai/</id>
    <summary type="text">Microsoft and OpenAI have signed a non-binding memorandum of understanding (MOU) for the next phase of our partnership. We are actively working to finalize contractual terms in a definitive agreement. Together, we remain focused on delivering the best AI tools for everyone, grounded in our shared commitment to safety.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:30:02 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Five Years On, Reels Reigns as India&#x27;s Top Short-Form Video Platform</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/five-years-on-reels-reigns-as-indias-top-short-form-video-platform/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/five-years-on-reels-reigns-as-indias-top-short-form-video-platform/</id>
    <summary type="text">Findings from a new Meta-commissioned IPSOS study show that Reels across our platforms is India’s top driver of daily video consumption ahead of other surveyed platforms.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:01:55 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#WhyIScience Q&amp;A: A structural biologist adopts a new role catalyzing collaborations</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/whyiscience-qa-structural-biologist-adopts-new-role-catalyzing-collaborations"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/whyiscience-qa-structural-biologist-adopts-new-role-catalyzing-collaborations</id>
    <summary type="text">A former drug discovery scientist, Gail Guo now helps advance research into novel cancer drugs as part of Broad’s alliance with Bayer.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:22:24 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Student Scores in Math, Science, Reading Slide Again on Nation’s Report Card - EdSurge News</title>
    <link href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-10-student-scores-in-math-science-reading-slide-again-on-nation-s-report-card"/>
    <id>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2025-09-10-student-scores-in-math-science-reading-slide-again-on-nation-s-report-card</id>
    <summary type="text">Exasperating. Depressing. Predictable. That’s how experts describe the latest results from the National Assessment of Educational Progress, also known ...</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA Blackwell Ultra Sets New Inference Records in MLPerf Debut | NVIDIA Technical Blog</title>
    <link href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/nvidia-blackwell-ultra-sets-new-inference-records-in-mlperf-debut/"/>
    <id>https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/nvidia-blackwell-ultra-sets-new-inference-records-in-mlperf-debut/</id>
    <summary type="text">As large language models (LLMs) grow larger, they get smarter, with open models from leading developers now featuring hundreds of billions of parameters. At the same time, today’s leading models are…</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA Rubin CPX Accelerates Inference Performance and Efficiency for 1M+ Token Context Workloads | NVIDIA Technical Blog</title>
    <link href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/nvidia-rubin-cpx-accelerates-inference-performance-and-efficiency-for-1m-token-context-workloads/"/>
    <id>https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/nvidia-rubin-cpx-accelerates-inference-performance-and-efficiency-for-1m-token-context-workloads/</id>
    <summary type="text">Inference has emerged as the new frontier of complexity in AI. Modern models are evolving into agentic systems capable of multi-step reasoning, persistent memory, and long-horizon context—enabling…</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remembering David Baltimore</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/remembering-david-baltimore"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/remembering-david-baltimore</id>
    <summary type="text">David Baltimore served as Chair of the Broad Institute Board of Scientific Counselors, was a member of our Board of Directors, and was essential in the formation of the Broad Institute itself. We asked our Founding Director, Eric S. Lander, to share some reflections with the Broad community.</summary>
    <updated>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 11:19:08 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Attach Text to Your Threads Posts and Share Longer Perspectives</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/attach-text-threads-posts-share-longer-perspectives/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/attach-text-threads-posts-share-longer-perspectives/</id>
    <summary type="text">We&#x27;re rolling out a way for you to attach up to 10,000 characters of text to a Threads post.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:00:51 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mass General Brigham launches genetic test to predict risk across eight cardiovascular conditions</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/mass-general-brigham-launches-genetic-test-predict-risk-across-eight-cardiovascular-conditions"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/mass-general-brigham-launches-genetic-test-predict-risk-across-eight-cardiovascular-conditions</id>
    <summary type="text">Developed in collaboration with Broad Clinical Labs and Mass General Brigham Laboratory for Molecular Medicine, the test provides a comprehensive view of a patient’s inherited heart disease risk. div.hero-section__author { display:none;}</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:35:14 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How massive datasets generated at Broad are powering the latest AI models in biology</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/how-massive-datasets-generated-broad-are-powering-latest-ai-models-biology"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/how-massive-datasets-generated-broad-are-powering-latest-ai-models-biology</id>
    <summary type="text">Broad scientists describe how data resources they helped build over more than a decade now form the foundation for cutting-edge AI and genome biology discoveries.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:10:36 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How Small Language Models Are Key to Scalable Agentic AI | NVIDIA Technical Blog</title>
    <link href="https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/how-small-language-models-are-key-to-scalable-agentic-ai/"/>
    <id>https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/how-small-language-models-are-key-to-scalable-agentic-ai/</id>
    <summary type="text">The rapid rise of agentic AI has reshaped how enterprises, developers, and entire industries think about automation and digital productivity. From software development workflows to enterprise process…</summary>
    <updated>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 18:00:42 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meta’s Kansas City Data Center and Upcoming AI-Optimized Data Centers</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/08/metas-kansas-city-data-center/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/08/metas-kansas-city-data-center/</id>
    <summary type="text">Our Kansas City data center is now operational, representing a $1 billion investment in Missouri and in our global infrastructure that brings our technologies to billions of people worldwide.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:00:26 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Unlocking the potential of manufacturing with cloud modernization - Microsoft Industry Blogs</title>
    <link href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/08/19/unlocking-the-potential-of-manufacturing-with-cloud-modernization/"/>
    <id>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/08/19/unlocking-the-potential-of-manufacturing-with-cloud-modernization/</id>
    <summary type="text">Uncover how manufacturers use AI and cloud to optimize operations, accelerate R&amp;D, and deliver real business value. Learn more.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Embracing AI-powered operations: A maturity path for manufacturers - Microsoft Industry Blogs</title>
    <link href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/08/07/embracing-ai-powered-operations-a-maturity-path-for-manufacturers/"/>
    <id>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/08/07/embracing-ai-powered-operations-a-maturity-path-for-manufacturers/</id>
    <summary type="text">Discover how manufacturers are embracing AI to boost efficiency, resilience, and innovation with Microsoft’s guidance. Learn more.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Breathing low-oxygen air slows Parkinson’s progression in mice</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/breathing-low-oxygen-air-slows-parkinsons-progression-mice"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/breathing-low-oxygen-air-slows-parkinsons-progression-mice</id>
    <summary type="text">Low-oxygen air prevented and even reversed symptoms in a mouse model of Parkinson’s disease.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 09:26:25 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Unlocking the Future of Surface Finishing with AI-Powered Adaptive Robotics</title>
    <link href="https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/unlocking-the-future-of-surface-finishing-with-ai-powered-adaptive-robotics/"/>
    <id>https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/unlocking-the-future-of-surface-finishing-with-ai-powered-adaptive-robotics/</id>
    <summary type="text">Discover how AI software is revolutionizing surface finishing by tackling labor shortages, increasing consistency, and accelerating automation.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 15:46:23 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Time-to-Value Speeds Up with Emerging AI-Enabled Robotics Automation</title>
    <link href="https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/time-to-value-speeds-up-with-emerging-ai-enabled-robotics-automation/"/>
    <id>https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/time-to-value-speeds-up-with-emerging-ai-enabled-robotics-automation/</id>
    <summary type="text">ABI Research report explores how AI-enabled robotics automation with a human element boosts manufacturing.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:41:28 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI in process manufacturing: From operational gains to strategic advantage - Microsoft Industry Blogs</title>
    <link href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/05/28/ai-in-process-manufacturing-from-operational-gains-to-strategic-advantage/"/>
    <id>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/05/28/ai-in-process-manufacturing-from-operational-gains-to-strategic-advantage/</id>
    <summary type="text">Explore insights into how manufacturers prioritize technology and where AI fits by reading the report &quot;Artificial Intelligence in Process Manufacturing.&quot;</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 28 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evolved gene editor inserts entire genes in human cells</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/evolved-gene-editor-inserts-entire-genes-human-cells"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/evolved-gene-editor-inserts-entire-genes-human-cells</id>
    <summary type="text">The new system is the first to use a DNA-mobilizing enzyme called a CRISPR-associated transposase to make targeted gene-sized edits at therapeutically useful levels in human cells.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:00:00 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Creating a resilient supply chain using connected data chains - Microsoft Industry Blogs</title>
    <link href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/05/05/creating-a-resilient-supply-chain-using-connected-data-chains/"/>
    <id>https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/industry/blog/manufacturing-and-mobility/manufacturing/2025/05/05/creating-a-resilient-supply-chain-using-connected-data-chains/</id>
    <summary type="text">Explore how Microsoft is enabling companies to easily navigate complexities and use technology with connected data chains and AI.</summary>
    <updated>Mon, 05 May 2025 15:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Enhancing MRO and Remanufacturing Work Processes with AI</title>
    <link href="https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/enhancing-mro-and-remanufacturing-work-processes-with-ai/"/>
    <id>https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/enhancing-mro-and-remanufacturing-work-processes-with-ai/</id>
    <summary type="text">Implementing Palladyne IQ robotic AI software can help autonomously manage component cleaning, prepare surfaces for the next production stage, and enhance the overall production process across MRO, remanufacturing, and other industries.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 10:25:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Speeding Robotics Automation with AI</title>
    <link href="https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/speeding-robotics-automation-with-ai/"/>
    <id>https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/speeding-robotics-automation-with-ai/</id>
    <summary type="text">ABI Research report explores AI-enabled robotics automation</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 17:03:03 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How Autonomous AI Tackles Quality Control Costs</title>
    <link href="https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/how-autonomous-ai-tackles-quality-control-costs/"/>
    <id>https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/how-autonomous-ai-tackles-quality-control-costs/</id>
    <summary type="text">Palladyne IQ robotic AI software helps automate inspection and streamline production across many industries.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 13:23:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Physical AI: Embracing AI’s Moment in Robotics</title>
    <link href="https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/physical-ai-embracing-ais-moment-in-robotics/"/>
    <id>https://www.palladyneai.com/blog/physical-ai-embracing-ais-moment-in-robotics/</id>
    <summary type="text">The rise of physical AI is having its breakthrough moment, like ChatGPT did in language processing in 2022. Read more.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:40:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gene editing extends lifespan in mouse model of prion disease</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/gene-editing-extends-lifespan-mouse-model-prion-disease"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/gene-editing-extends-lifespan-mouse-model-prion-disease</id>
    <summary type="text">A single-letter edit in DNA reduces levels of the disease-causing prion protein in the brain and could lead to a preventative, one-time treatment for the deadly neurodegenerative disorder.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 05:00:00 -0500</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists engineer CRISPR enzymes that evade the immune system</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/scientists-engineer-crispr-enzymes-evade-immune-system"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/scientists-engineer-crispr-enzymes-evade-immune-system</id>
    <summary type="text">The new genome-editing tools could lead to safer, more efficient gene therapies.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:00:00 -0500</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Researchers devise new way to target and correct disease-related proteins</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/researchers-devise-new-way-target-and-correct-disease-related-proteins"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/researchers-devise-new-way-target-and-correct-disease-related-proteins</id>
    <summary type="text">Broad scientists built a diverse library of compounds and found one that stabilizes a dysfunctional protein in Crohn’s disease, demonstrating their library’s potential to uncover new therapeutic strategies.</summary>
    <updated>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:17:49 -0500</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaQubit tackles one of quantum computing’s biggest challenges</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaqubit-tackles-one-of-quantum-computings-biggest-challenges/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaqubit-tackles-one-of-quantum-computings-biggest-challenges/</id>
    <summary type="text">AlphaQubit is an AI-based decoder that identifies quantum computing errors with state-of-the-art accuracy.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New drug triggers rapid cell death in cancer models</title>
    <link href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/new-drug-triggers-rapid-cell-death-cancer-models"/>
    <id>https://www.broadinstitute.org/news/new-drug-triggers-rapid-cell-death-cancer-models</id>
    <summary type="text">BRD-810 inhibits the MCL1 protein and reactivates apoptosis in tumor cells, displaying therapeutic potential in animal models.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 11:11:58 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>All NASA News - NASA</title>
    <link href="https://www.nasa.gov/news/recently-published/"/>
    <id>https://www.nasa.gov/news/recently-published/</id>
    <summary type="text">Stay up-to-date with the latest content from NASA as we explore the universe and discover more about our home planet.</summary>
    <updated>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 08:59:39 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA Media Contacts - NASA</title>
    <link href="https://www.nasa.gov/news/media-contacts/"/>
    <id>https://www.nasa.gov/news/media-contacts/</id>
    <summary type="text">Media Contacts Roxana Bardan Mars Sample Return 771-200-7217 Gerelle Dodson NASA Workforce, STEM Engagement 202-358-1600 Jennifer Dooren Deputy News Chief,</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 14:53:17 -0400</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA News</title>
    <link href="https://www.nasa.gov/news/"/>
    <id>https://www.nasa.gov/news/</id>
    <summary type="text">Resources for news media, including NASA news contacts and archived news material</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 13:25:24 -0500</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/</id>
    <summary type="text">Discover our latest AI breakthroughs, projects, and updates.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaGenome: AI for better understanding the genome</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphagenome-ai-for-better-understanding-the-genome/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphagenome-ai-for-better-understanding-the-genome/</id>
    <summary type="text">Introducing a new, unifying DNA sequence model that advances regulatory variant-effect prediction and promises to shed new light on genome function — now available via API.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A catalogue of genetic mutations to help pinpoint the cause of diseases</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/a-catalogue-of-genetic-mutations-to-help-pinpoint-the-cause-of-diseases/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/a-catalogue-of-genetic-mutations-to-help-pinpoint-the-cause-of-diseases/</id>
    <summary type="text">New AI tool classifies the effects of 71 million ‘missense’ mutations 
Uncovering the root causes of disease is one of the greatest challenges in human genetics. With millions of possible...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaProteo generates novel proteins for biology and health research</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaproteo-generates-novel-proteins-for-biology-and-health-research/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaproteo-generates-novel-proteins-for-biology-and-health-research/</id>
    <summary type="text">New AI system designs proteins that successfully bind to target molecules, with potential for advancing drug design, disease understanding and more.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaEvolve: A Gemini-powered coding agent for designing advanced algorithms</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaevolve-a-gemini-powered-coding-agent-for-designing-advanced-algorithms/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaevolve-a-gemini-powered-coding-agent-for-designing-advanced-algorithms/</id>
    <summary type="text">New AI agent evolves algorithms for math and practical applications in computing by combining the creativity of large language models with automated evaluators</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI achieves silver-medal standard solving International Mathematical Olympiad problems</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/ai-solves-imo-problems-at-silver-medal-level/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/ai-solves-imo-problems-at-silver-medal-level/</id>
    <summary type="text">Breakthrough models AlphaProof and AlphaGeometry 2 solve advanced reasoning problems in mathematics</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>