<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Nanotech (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://4thwave.ai"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/nanotech.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:nanotech</id>
  <updated>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:42:07 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Court rulings increasingly demand scientific certainty—but the case of titanium dioxide shows that&#x27;s not always possible</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-court-demand-scientific-certainty-case.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-court-demand-scientific-certainty-case.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Last month, courts on both sides of the Atlantic delivered a clear verdict: When classifying titanium dioxide as carcinogenic, regulatory agencies had overreached.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New light-powered gears fit inside a strand of hair</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-powered-gears-strand-hair.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-powered-gears-strand-hair.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers at the University of Gothenburg have made light-powered gears on a micrometer scale. This paves the way for the smallest on-chip motors in history, which can fit inside a strand of hair. The research is published in the journal Nature Communications.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bioengineers explore how tumor mechanics and tiny messengers could shape the future of cancer research</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-bioengineers-explore-tumor-mechanics-tiny.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-bioengineers-explore-tumor-mechanics-tiny.html</id>
    <summary type="text">When Ph.D. student Kshitiz Parihar began combing through dozens of research papers on two seemingly different topics—tumor mechanics and extracellular vesicles, tiny packages of proteins and genetic material secreted by cells—he noticed something surprising: the two fields were speaking to each other.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hybrid nanoantennas enable light capture from diamond defects</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-hybrid-nanoantennas-enable-capture-diamond.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-hybrid-nanoantennas-enable-capture-diamond.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem and the Humboldt University in Berlin have developed a way to capture nearly all the light emitted from tiny diamond defects known as color centers. By placing nanodiamonds into specially designed hybrid nanoantennas with extreme precision, the team achieved record photon collection at room temperature—a necessary step for quantum technologies such as quantum sensors, and quantum-secured communications.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thermal trigger: Scientists develop heat-activated protein control for targeted cell death</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-thermal-trigger-scientists-protein-cell.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-thermal-trigger-scientists-protein-cell.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers at the Nano Life Science Institute (WPI-NanoLSI), Kanazawa University, report in ACS Nano, how proteins in cells can be controllably activated through heating, an effect that can be used to initiate programmed cell death.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scalable strategy produces high-quality black phosphorus nanoribbons for electronics</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scalable-strategy-high-quality-black.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scalable-strategy-high-quality-black.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Black phosphorus nanoribbons (BPNRs), thin and narrow ribbon-like strips of black phosphorus, are known to exhibit highly advantageous electronic properties, including a tunable bandgap. This essentially means that the energy difference between the region where electrons are bound together (i.e., valence band) and that where electrons move freely (i.e., conduction band) can be easily controlled by adjusting the width of the nanoribbons.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lipid nanoparticles enable targeted RNA therapy for inflammatory bowel diseases</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-lipid-nanoparticles-enable-rna-therapy.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-lipid-nanoparticles-enable-rna-therapy.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers at Tel Aviv University have developed a new approach for using locked nucleic acids (LNAs)—a particularly stable type of RNA—to treat inflammatory bowel diseases such as Crohn&#x27;s disease and ulcerative colitis. The researchers encapsulated selected LNA molecules, which silence a key gene in colitis, within lipid (fat) nanoparticles that serve as targeted drug carriers and injected the nanoparticles into colitis-model mice.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nanoscale optical device enables independent control of light intensity and phase using electricity</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nanoscale-optical-device-enables-independent.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nanoscale-optical-device-enables-independent.html</id>
    <summary type="text">A nanoscale optical device has been developed that allows independent control over the intensity and phase of light. By applying voltage, this innovative device can freely manipulate the phase and magnitude of second-harmonic (SH) light, opening new avenues for advanced quantum communication and information processing technologies. The research is published in Science Advances.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Proximity screening pushes graphene electronic quality to record levels</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-proximity-screening-graphene-electronic-quality.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-proximity-screening-graphene-electronic-quality.html</id>
    <summary type="text">In a new Nature study, researchers at the University of Manchester have achieved unprecedented electronic quality in graphene by developing a proximity screening technique that places conducting gates just one nanometer away from the carbon lattice.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Spinning bioreactors increase yield of extracellular vesicles for more affordable targeted medicine</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-bioreactors-yield-extracellular-vesicles-medicine.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-bioreactors-yield-extracellular-vesicles-medicine.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Inside cells there are tiny particles, known as extracellular vesicles, that store and move molecules. Our cells naturally package beneficial proteins and healing compounds into these tiny bubbles, dispatching them to where they are needed to deliver molecular cargo or to communicate with other cells.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>&#x27;Wiggling&#x27; atoms may lead to smaller, more efficient electronics</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-wiggling-atoms-smaller-efficient-electronics.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-wiggling-atoms-smaller-efficient-electronics.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers at Michigan State University have figured out how to use a fast laser to wiggle atoms in a way that temporarily changes the behavior of their host material. Their novel approach could lead to smaller and more efficient electronics—like smartphones—in the future.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MXene electrode material withstands seawater corrosion in hydrogen production</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-mxene-electrode-material-seawater-corrosion.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-mxene-electrode-material-seawater-corrosion.html</id>
    <summary type="text">A research team has developed a composite catalyst using the novel material MXene that suppresses the generation of chloride ions—one of the key challenges in seawater electrolysis. This research outcome is expected to accelerate the practical application of seawater electrolysis technology by enabling stable hydrogen production even in seawater.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Harvard’s salt trick could turn billions of tons of hair into eco-friendly materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250916221913.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250916221913.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists at Harvard have discovered how salts like lithium bromide break down tough proteins such as keratin—not by attacking the proteins directly, but by altering the surrounding water structure. This breakthrough opens the door to a cleaner, more sustainable way to recycle wool, feathers, and hair into valuable materials, potentially replacing plastics and fueling new industries.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny magnetic spirals unlock the future of spintronics</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250913232933.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250913232933.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists in Korea have engineered magnetic nanohelices that can control electron spin with extraordinary precision at room temperature. By combining structural chirality and magnetism, these nanoscale helices can filter spins without complex circuitry or cooling. The breakthrough not only demonstrates a way to program handedness in inorganic nanomaterials but also opens the door to scalable, energy-efficient spintronic devices that could revolutionize computing.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists just built a detector that could finally catch dark matter</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Physicists have unveiled a new superconducting detector sensitive enough to hunt dark matter particles smaller than electrons. By capturing faint photon signals, the device pushes the search into uncharted territory.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The invisible plastic threat you can finally see</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers in Germany and Australia have created a simple but powerful tool to detect nanoplastics—tiny, invisible particles that can slip through skin and even the blood-brain barrier. Using an &amp;quot;optical sieve&amp;quot; test strip viewed under a regular microscope, these particles reveal themselves through striking color changes.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny gold quantum needles with astonishing powers discovered</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists at the University of Tokyo have unveiled “gold quantum needles,” a newly discovered nanocluster structure formed under unusual synthesis conditions. Unlike typical spherical clusters, these elongated, pencil-shaped formations display unique quantum behaviors and respond to near-infrared light, making them promising tools for biomedical imaging and energy applications.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This tiny iron catalyst could transform the future of clean energy</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250827010717.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250827010717.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Hydrogen fuel cells could power cars, devices, and homes with nothing but water as a byproduct—but platinum’s cost holds them back. Chinese researchers have now unveiled a breakthrough iron-based catalyst that could rival platinum while boosting efficiency and durability. With its clever “inner activation, outer protection” design, this new catalyst not only reduces harmful byproducts but also shatters performance records, potentially paving the way for cleaner, cheaper, and more practical hydrogen energy.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists unlock nature’s secret to superfast mini robots</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250824031532.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250824031532.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Ripple bugs’ fan-like legs inspired engineers to build the Rhagobot, a tiny robot with self-morphing fans. By mimicking these insects’ passive, ultra-fast movements, the robot gains speed, control, and endurance without extra energy—potentially transforming aquatic microrobotics.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny quantum dots unlock the future of unbreakable encryption</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250822073814.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250822073814.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">By using quantum dots and smart encryption protocols, researchers overcame a 40-year barrier in quantum communication, showing that secure networks don’t need perfect hardware to outperform today’s best systems.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This simple magnetic trick could change quantum computing forever</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250816113508.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250816113508.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers have unveiled a new quantum material that could make quantum computers much more stable by using magnetism to protect delicate qubits from environmental disturbances. Unlike traditional approaches that rely on rare spin-orbit interactions, this method uses magnetic interactions—common in many materials—to create robust topological excitations. Combined with a new computational tool for finding such materials, this breakthrough could pave the way for practical, disturbance-resistant quantum computers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists just made vibrations so precise they can spot a single molecule</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250814094658.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250814094658.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Rice University scientists have discovered a way to make tiny vibrations, called phonons, interfere with each other more strongly than ever before. Using a special sandwich of silver, graphene, and silicon carbide, they created a record-breaking effect so sensitive it can detect a single molecule without labels or complex equipment. This breakthrough could open new possibilities for powerful sensors, quantum devices, and technologies that control heat and energy at the smallest scales.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI finds hidden safe zones inside a fusion reactor</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250813083605.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250813083605.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists have developed a lightning-fast AI tool called HEAT-ML that can spot hidden “safe zones” inside a fusion reactor where parts are protected from blistering plasma heat. Finding these areas, known as magnetic shadows, is key to keeping reactors running safely and moving fusion energy closer to reality.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>