<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>4thWave AI — Nanotech (Aggregated)</title>
    <link>https://4thwave.ai</link>
    <description>Aggregated feed generated by 4thWave AI.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 02:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Atom-thin crystals provide new way to power the future of computer memory</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-atom-thin-crystals-power-future.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-atom-thin-crystals-power-future.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Picture the smartphone in your pocket, the data centers powering artificial intelligence, or the wearable health monitors that track your heartbeat. All of them rely on energy-hungry memory chips to store and process information. As demand for computing resources continues to soar, so does the need for memory devices that are smaller, faster, and far more efficient.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-switch achieves first directed, gated flow of excitons</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nano-gated-excitons.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nano-gated-excitons.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A new nanostructure acts like a wire and switch that can, for the first time, control and direct the flow of quantum quasiparticles called excitons at room temperature.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circuits invisible to the naked eye: New technique shrinks microchips beyond current size limits</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-circuits-invisible-naked-eye-technique.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-circuits-invisible-naked-eye-technique.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Johns Hopkins researchers have discovered new materials and a new process that could advance the ever-escalating quest to make smaller, faster and affordable microchips used across modern electronics—in everything from cellphones to cars, appliances to airplanes.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists develop hydrogel platform for long-lasting, precision drug delivery</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scientists-hydrogel-platform-precision-drug.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scientists-hydrogel-platform-precision-drug.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Taking medications on time, in the right dose and for the prescribed duration can be challenging for patients, and failure to do so comes with steep costs, causing 10% of hospitalizations and billions in avoidable spending in the United States alone, according to some estimates. A team of Rice University scientists has developed a new drug delivery platform that could make it easier to complete a therapeutic regimen and even boost drug efficacy.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic nanocatalysts: What really happens during catalysis</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-metallic-nanocatalysts-catalysis.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-metallic-nanocatalysts-catalysis.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Using a combination of spectromicroscopy at BESSY II and microscopic analyses at DESY's NanoLab, a team has gained new insights into the chemical behavior of nanocatalysts during catalysis.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanobots play &#x27;follow the leader&#x27; by chasing chemical trails in microfluidic device</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nanobots-play-leader-chemical-trails.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nanobots-play-leader-chemical-trails.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Researchers at Penn State demonstrate the first steps in the design of tiny particles that can perform specialized tasks, such as targeted delivery of drugs or other cargo.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cat whiskers inspire highly sensitive, next-generation wearable pressure sensors</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-cat-whiskers-highly-sensitive-generation.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-cat-whiskers-highly-sensitive-generation.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Flexible pressure sensors can detect subtle mechanical stimuli, making them suitable for use in wearable sensors for human health monitoring and motion analysis. However, current sensors suffer from insufficient sensitivity, poor durability, and subpar stability. In a new study, taking inspiration from cat whiskers, researchers developed novel biomass fiber/sodium alginate aerogel (BFA)-based sensors that demonstrated excellent pressure sensitivity, durability, and rapid response, while being suitable for human physiological monitoring and motion analysis.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new way to prevent icing problems for aircraft and drones</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-icing-problems-aircraft-drones.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-icing-problems-aircraft-drones.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Ice formation on propeller blades or aircraft wings can cause major problems. It can limit flight time, increase costs and pose safety and environmental risks.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon nanowires self-assemble into macroscopic networks for advanced materials</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-silicon-nanowires-macroscopic-networks-advanced.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-silicon-nanowires-macroscopic-networks-advanced.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Researchers at IMDEA Materials Institute have developed a pioneering method to assemble silicon nanowires into ordered, macroscopic networks: a key step toward expanding their industrial applications.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sponge-like gold nanoparticles could upgrade ovarian cancer diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-sponge-gold-nanoparticles-ovarian-cancer.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-sponge-gold-nanoparticles-ovarian-cancer.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A project led by University of Queensland Ph.D. student Javeria Bashir has produced specially crafted gold nanoparticles that can highlight cancer markers in samples like urine, saliva, or blood. Bashir said she hoped to use her gold nanoparticles to help improve survival rates for a cancer that is considered particularly deadly.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#x27;Bottlebrush&#x27; particles deliver big chemotherapy payloads directly to cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-bottlebrush-particles-big-chemotherapy-payloads.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-bottlebrush-particles-big-chemotherapy-payloads.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Using tiny particles shaped like bottlebrushes, MIT chemists have found a way to deliver a large range of chemotherapy drugs directly to tumor cells.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core technology developed for ultra-high-resolution quantum dot displays</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-core-technology-ultra-high-resolution.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-core-technology-ultra-high-resolution.html</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[A research team has developed a direct optical lithography (DOL) technology that patterns quantum dots (QDs) at ultra-high resolution using only light, without photoresist. Through this, they also provided guidelines for selecting cross-linkers essential for fabricating high-performance QLEDs. This achievement is regarded as a core fundamental technology that can be applied to a wide range of optoelectronic devices, including micro-QLEDs, ultra-high-resolution displays, transparent electronic devices, and next-generation image sensors.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists just built a detector that could finally catch dark matter</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Physicists have unveiled a new superconducting detector sensitive enough to hunt dark matter particles smaller than electrons. By capturing faint photon signals, the device pushes the search into uncharted territory.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The invisible plastic threat you can finally see</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Researchers in Germany and Australia have created a simple but powerful tool to detect nanoplastics—tiny, invisible particles that can slip through skin and even the blood-brain barrier. Using an &quot;optical sieve&quot; test strip viewed under a regular microscope, these particles reveal themselves through striking color changes.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny gold quantum needles with astonishing powers discovered</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Scientists at the University of Tokyo have unveiled “gold quantum needles,” a newly discovered nanocluster structure formed under unusual synthesis conditions. Unlike typical spherical clusters, these elongated, pencil-shaped formations display unique quantum behaviors and respond to near-infrared light, making them promising tools for biomedical imaging and energy applications.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This tiny iron catalyst could transform the future of clean energy</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250827010717.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250827010717.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Hydrogen fuel cells could power cars, devices, and homes with nothing but water as a byproduct—but platinum’s cost holds them back. Chinese researchers have now unveiled a breakthrough iron-based catalyst that could rival platinum while boosting efficiency and durability. With its clever “inner activation, outer protection” design, this new catalyst not only reduces harmful byproducts but also shatters performance records, potentially paving the way for cleaner, cheaper, and more practical hydrogen energy.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists unlock nature’s secret to superfast mini robots</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250824031532.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250824031532.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Ripple bugs’ fan-like legs inspired engineers to build the Rhagobot, a tiny robot with self-morphing fans. By mimicking these insects’ passive, ultra-fast movements, the robot gains speed, control, and endurance without extra energy—potentially transforming aquatic microrobotics.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny quantum dots unlock the future of unbreakable encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250822073814.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250822073814.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[By using quantum dots and smart encryption protocols, researchers overcame a 40-year barrier in quantum communication, showing that secure networks don’t need perfect hardware to outperform today’s best systems.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This simple magnetic trick could change quantum computing forever</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250816113508.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250816113508.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Researchers have unveiled a new quantum material that could make quantum computers much more stable by using magnetism to protect delicate qubits from environmental disturbances. Unlike traditional approaches that rely on rare spin-orbit interactions, this method uses magnetic interactions—common in many materials—to create robust topological excitations. Combined with a new computational tool for finding such materials, this breakthrough could pave the way for practical, disturbance-resistant quantum computers.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists just made vibrations so precise they can spot a single molecule</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250814094658.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250814094658.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Rice University scientists have discovered a way to make tiny vibrations, called phonons, interfere with each other more strongly than ever before. Using a special sandwich of silver, graphene, and silicon carbide, they created a record-breaking effect so sensitive it can detect a single molecule without labels or complex equipment. This breakthrough could open new possibilities for powerful sensors, quantum devices, and technologies that control heat and energy at the smallest scales.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI finds hidden safe zones inside a fusion reactor</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250813083605.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250813083605.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Scientists have developed a lightning-fast AI tool called HEAT-ML that can spot hidden “safe zones” inside a fusion reactor where parts are protected from blistering plasma heat. Finding these areas, known as magnetic shadows, is key to keeping reactors running safely and moving fusion energy closer to reality.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny gold “super atoms” could spark a quantum revolution</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250810093250.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250810093250.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Scientists have found that microscopic gold clusters can act like the world’s most accurate quantum systems, while being far easier to scale up. With tunable spin properties and mass production potential, they could transform quantum computing and sensing.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concrete that lasts centuries and captures carbon? AI just made it possible</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250723045707.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250723045707.htm</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[Imagine concrete that not only survives wildfires and extreme weather, but heals itself and absorbs carbon from the air. Scientists at USC have created an AI model called Allegro-FM that simulates billions of atoms at once, helping design futuristic materials like carbon-neutral concrete. This tech could transform cities by reducing emissions, extending building lifespans, and mimicking the ancient durability of Roman concrete—all thanks to a massive leap in AI-driven atomic modeling.]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>