<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Nanotech (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://4thwave.ai"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/nanotech.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:nanotech</id>
  <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:41:56 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>MXene electrode material withstands seawater corrosion in hydrogen production</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-mxene-electrode-material-seawater-corrosion.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-mxene-electrode-material-seawater-corrosion.html</id>
    <summary type="text">A research team has developed a composite catalyst using the novel material MXene that suppresses the generation of chloride ions—one of the key challenges in seawater electrolysis. This research outcome is expected to accelerate the practical application of seawater electrolysis technology by enabling stable hydrogen production even in seawater.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Proximity screening pushes graphene electronic quality to record levels</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-proximity-screening-graphene-electronic-quality.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-proximity-screening-graphene-electronic-quality.html</id>
    <summary type="text">In a new Nature study, researchers at the University of Manchester have achieved unprecedented electronic quality in graphene by developing a proximity screening technique that places conducting gates just one nanometer away from the carbon lattice.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists discover how nanoplastics disrupt brain energy metabolism</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scientists-nanoplastics-disrupt-brain-energy.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scientists-nanoplastics-disrupt-brain-energy.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists from the Trinity Biomedical Sciences Institute (TBSI) have discovered how nanoplastics—even smaller than microplastics—disrupt energy metabolism in brain cells. Their findings may have implications for better understanding neurodegenerative diseases characterized by declining neurological or brain function, and even shed new light on issues with learning and memory.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Next-generation nanoengineered switches can cut heat loss in electronics</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-generation-nanoengineered-loss-electronics.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-generation-nanoengineered-loss-electronics.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Electronic devices lose energy as heat due to the movement of electrons. Now, a breakthrough in nanoengineering has produced a new kind of switch that matches the performance of the best traditional designs while pushing beyond the power-consumption limits of modern electronics.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Atom-thin crystals provide new way to power the future of computer memory</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-atom-thin-crystals-power-future.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-atom-thin-crystals-power-future.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Picture the smartphone in your pocket, the data centers powering artificial intelligence, or the wearable health monitors that track your heartbeat. All of them rely on energy-hungry memory chips to store and process information. As demand for computing resources continues to soar, so does the need for memory devices that are smaller, faster, and far more efficient.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Circuits invisible to the naked eye: New technique shrinks microchips beyond current size limits</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-circuits-invisible-naked-eye-technique.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-circuits-invisible-naked-eye-technique.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Johns Hopkins researchers have discovered new materials and a new process that could advance the ever-escalating quest to make smaller, faster and affordable microchips used across modern electronics—in everything from cellphones to cars, appliances to airplanes.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nano-switch achieves first directed, gated flow of excitons</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nano-gated-excitons.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nano-gated-excitons.html</id>
    <summary type="text">A new nanostructure acts like a wire and switch that can, for the first time, control and direct the flow of quantum quasiparticles called excitons at room temperature.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nanobots play &#x27;follow the leader&#x27; by chasing chemical trails in microfluidic device</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nanobots-play-leader-chemical-trails.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-nanobots-play-leader-chemical-trails.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers at Penn State demonstrate the first steps in the design of tiny particles that can perform specialized tasks, such as targeted delivery of drugs or other cargo.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists develop hydrogel platform for long-lasting, precision drug delivery</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scientists-hydrogel-platform-precision-drug.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-scientists-hydrogel-platform-precision-drug.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Taking medications on time, in the right dose and for the prescribed duration can be challenging for patients, and failure to do so comes with steep costs, causing 10% of hospitalizations and billions in avoidable spending in the United States alone, according to some estimates. A team of Rice University scientists has developed a new drug delivery platform that could make it easier to complete a therapeutic regimen and even boost drug efficacy.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Metallic nanocatalysts: What really happens during catalysis</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-metallic-nanocatalysts-catalysis.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-metallic-nanocatalysts-catalysis.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Using a combination of spectromicroscopy at BESSY II and microscopic analyses at DESY&#x27;s NanoLab, a team has gained new insights into the chemical behavior of nanocatalysts during catalysis.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cat whiskers inspire highly sensitive, next-generation wearable pressure sensors</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-cat-whiskers-highly-sensitive-generation.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-cat-whiskers-highly-sensitive-generation.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Flexible pressure sensors can detect subtle mechanical stimuli, making them suitable for use in wearable sensors for human health monitoring and motion analysis. However, current sensors suffer from insufficient sensitivity, poor durability, and subpar stability. In a new study, taking inspiration from cat whiskers, researchers developed novel biomass fiber/sodium alginate aerogel (BFA)-based sensors that demonstrated excellent pressure sensitivity, durability, and rapid response, while being suitable for human physiological monitoring and motion analysis.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A new way to prevent icing problems for aircraft and drones</title>
    <link href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-icing-problems-aircraft-drones.html"/>
    <id>https://phys.org/news/2025-09-icing-problems-aircraft-drones.html</id>
    <summary type="text">Ice formation on propeller blades or aircraft wings can cause major problems. It can limit flight time, increase costs and pose safety and environmental risks.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny magnetic spirals unlock the future of spintronics</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250913232933.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250913232933.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists in Korea have engineered magnetic nanohelices that can control electron spin with extraordinary precision at room temperature. By combining structural chirality and magnetism, these nanoscale helices can filter spins without complex circuitry or cooling. The breakthrough not only demonstrates a way to program handedness in inorganic nanomaterials but also opens the door to scalable, energy-efficient spintronic devices that could revolutionize computing.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists just built a detector that could finally catch dark matter</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000302.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Physicists have unveiled a new superconducting detector sensitive enough to hunt dark matter particles smaller than electrons. By capturing faint photon signals, the device pushes the search into uncharted territory.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The invisible plastic threat you can finally see</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250910000240.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers in Germany and Australia have created a simple but powerful tool to detect nanoplastics—tiny, invisible particles that can slip through skin and even the blood-brain barrier. Using an &amp;quot;optical sieve&amp;quot; test strip viewed under a regular microscope, these particles reveal themselves through striking color changes.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny gold quantum needles with astonishing powers discovered</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250905180734.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists at the University of Tokyo have unveiled “gold quantum needles,” a newly discovered nanocluster structure formed under unusual synthesis conditions. Unlike typical spherical clusters, these elongated, pencil-shaped formations display unique quantum behaviors and respond to near-infrared light, making them promising tools for biomedical imaging and energy applications.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This tiny iron catalyst could transform the future of clean energy</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250827010717.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250827010717.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Hydrogen fuel cells could power cars, devices, and homes with nothing but water as a byproduct—but platinum’s cost holds them back. Chinese researchers have now unveiled a breakthrough iron-based catalyst that could rival platinum while boosting efficiency and durability. With its clever “inner activation, outer protection” design, this new catalyst not only reduces harmful byproducts but also shatters performance records, potentially paving the way for cleaner, cheaper, and more practical hydrogen energy.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists unlock nature’s secret to superfast mini robots</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250824031532.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250824031532.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Ripple bugs’ fan-like legs inspired engineers to build the Rhagobot, a tiny robot with self-morphing fans. By mimicking these insects’ passive, ultra-fast movements, the robot gains speed, control, and endurance without extra energy—potentially transforming aquatic microrobotics.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny quantum dots unlock the future of unbreakable encryption</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250822073814.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250822073814.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">By using quantum dots and smart encryption protocols, researchers overcame a 40-year barrier in quantum communication, showing that secure networks don’t need perfect hardware to outperform today’s best systems.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This simple magnetic trick could change quantum computing forever</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250816113508.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250816113508.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers have unveiled a new quantum material that could make quantum computers much more stable by using magnetism to protect delicate qubits from environmental disturbances. Unlike traditional approaches that rely on rare spin-orbit interactions, this method uses magnetic interactions—common in many materials—to create robust topological excitations. Combined with a new computational tool for finding such materials, this breakthrough could pave the way for practical, disturbance-resistant quantum computers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists just made vibrations so precise they can spot a single molecule</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250814094658.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250814094658.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Rice University scientists have discovered a way to make tiny vibrations, called phonons, interfere with each other more strongly than ever before. Using a special sandwich of silver, graphene, and silicon carbide, they created a record-breaking effect so sensitive it can detect a single molecule without labels or complex equipment. This breakthrough could open new possibilities for powerful sensors, quantum devices, and technologies that control heat and energy at the smallest scales.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI finds hidden safe zones inside a fusion reactor</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250813083605.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250813083605.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists have developed a lightning-fast AI tool called HEAT-ML that can spot hidden “safe zones” inside a fusion reactor where parts are protected from blistering plasma heat. Finding these areas, known as magnetic shadows, is key to keeping reactors running safely and moving fusion energy closer to reality.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tiny gold “super atoms” could spark a quantum revolution</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250810093250.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250810093250.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientists have found that microscopic gold clusters can act like the world’s most accurate quantum systems, while being far easier to scale up. With tunable spin properties and mass production potential, they could transform quantum computing and sensing.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>