<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Satya Nadella (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://www.4thwaveai.com"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/satya-nadella.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:satya-nadella</id>
  <updated>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 05:40:56 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing Microsoft Marketplace — Thousands of solutions. Millions of customers. One Marketplace. - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/25/introducing-microsoft-marketplace-thousands-of-solutions-millions-of-customers-one-marketplace/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/25/introducing-microsoft-marketplace-thousands-of-solutions-millions-of-customers-one-marketplace/</id>
    <summary type="text">A new breed of industry-leading company is taking shape — Frontier Firms. These organizations blend human ambition with AI-powered technology to reshape how innovation is scaled, work is orchestrated and value is created. They’re accelerating AI transformation to enrich employee experiences, reinvent customer engagement, reshape business processes and unlock creativity and innovation. To empower customers...</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 14:00:01 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Inside the world’s most powerful AI datacenter - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/18/inside-the-worlds-most-powerful-ai-datacenter/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/18/inside-the-worlds-most-powerful-ai-datacenter/</id>
    <summary type="text">This week we have introduced a wave of purpose-built datacenters and infrastructure investments we are making around the world to support the global adoption of cutting-edge AI workloads and cloud services. Today in Wisconsin we introduced Fairwater, our newest US AI datacenter, the largest and most sophisticated AI factory we’ve built yet. In addition to...</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:00:02 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Microsoft leads shift beyond data unification to organization, delivering next-gen AI readiness with new Microsoft Fabric capabilities - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/16/microsoft-leads-shift-beyond-data-unification-to-organization-delivering-next-gen-ai-readiness-with-new-microsoft-fabric-capabilities/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/16/microsoft-leads-shift-beyond-data-unification-to-organization-delivering-next-gen-ai-readiness-with-new-microsoft-fabric-capabilities/</id>
    <summary type="text">We’re in a hinge moment for AI. The experiments are over and the real work has begun. Centralizing data, once the finish line, is now the starting point. The definition of “AI readiness” is evolving as increasingly sophisticated agents demand rich, contextualized data grounded in business operations to deliver meaningful results. What sets leaders apart...</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:00:04 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chief Marketing Officer, Commercial Cloud &amp; AI</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/ataylor/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/ataylor/</id>
    <summary type="text">Sep 25, 2025 | Alysa Taylor - Chief Marketing Officer, Commercial Cloud &amp; AI</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Executive Vice President, Cloud + AI</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/scottguthrie/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/scottguthrie/</id>
    <summary type="text">Sep 18, 2025 | Scott Guthrie - Executive Vice President, Cloud + AI</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jessica Hawk, Author at The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/jessiahawk/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/jessiahawk/</id>
    <summary type="text">Sep 16, 2025 | Jessica Hawk - Corporate Vice President, Data, AI, and Digital Applications, Product Marketing</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>