<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Structural Battery Composites (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://www.4thwaveai.com"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/structural-battery-composites.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:structural-battery-composites</id>
  <updated>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:39:52 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>New cooling breakthrough nearly doubles efficiency</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250919085242.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250919085242.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">CHESS thin-film materials nearly double refrigeration efficiency compared to traditional methods. Scalable and versatile, they promise applications from household cooling to space exploration.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Light-powered chip makes AI 100 times more efficient</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Artificial intelligence is consuming enormous amounts of energy, but researchers at the University of Florida have built a chip that could change everything by using light instead of electricity for a core AI function. By etching microscopic lenses directly onto silicon, they’ve enabled laser-powered computations that cut power use dramatically while maintaining near-perfect accuracy.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why recycling ‘dead’ batteries could save billions and slash pollution</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Lithium battery recycling offers a powerful solution to rising demand, with discarded batteries still holding most of their valuable materials. Compared to mining, recycling slashes emissions and resource use while unlocking major economic potential. Yet infrastructure, policy, and technology hurdles must still be overcome.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI just found 5 powerful materials that could replace lithium batteries</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">AI is helping scientists crack the code on next-gen batteries that could replace lithium-ion tech. By discovering novel porous materials, researchers may have paved the way for more powerful and sustainable energy storage using abundant elements like magnesium.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists discover salt that makes batteries last 10x longer</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">A team at KAUST has revealed that the short lifespan of aqueous batteries is primarily due to &amp;quot;free water&amp;quot; molecules triggering harmful chemical reactions at the anode. By adding affordable sulfate salts like zinc sulfate, they significantly reduced this issue—boosting battery life over tenfold. The sulfate acts as a “water glue,” stabilizing the water structure and halting the energy-wasting reactions. Not only is this solution simple and cost-effective, but early results suggest it may be a universal fix for various types of metal-anode aqueous batteries.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You hear the beep, but can’t find the car: The hidden flaw in electric vehicle safety</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">As electric vehicles grow more popular, their warning sounds may not be doing enough to protect pedestrians. A Swedish study shows that these signals are hard to locate, especially when multiple vehicles are involved, leaving people unable to tell where danger is coming from or how many cars are nearby.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Discovery could boost solid-state battery performance</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers have discovered that the mixing of small particles between two solid electrolytes can generate an effect called a &amp;apos;space charge layer,&amp;apos; an accumulation of electric charge at the interface between the two materials. The finding could aid the development of batteries with solid electrolytes, called solid-state batteries, for applications including mobile devices and electric vehicles.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Listening to electrons talk</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers present new experimental and theoretical results for the bound electron g-factor in lithium-like tin which has a much higher nuclear charge than any previous measurement. The experimental accuracy reached a level of 0.5 parts per billion. Using an enhanced interelectronic QED method, the theoretical prediction for the g-factor reached a precision of 6 parts per billion.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EV battery recycling key to future lithium supplies</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Lightweight, powerful lithium-ion batteries are crucial for the transition to electric vehicles, and global demand for lithium is set to grow rapidly over the next 25 years. A new analysis looks at how new mining operations and battery recycling could meet that demand. Recycling could play a big role in easing supply constraints, the researchers found.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Spectroscopic probe of spin current - Nature Materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02365-w"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02365-w</id>
    <summary type="text">Magnetism</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Imaging isospin order in rhombohedral graphene reveals anisotropy in correlated states - Nature Physics</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03036-y"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03036-y</id>
    <summary type="text">The microscopic magnetic textures of isospin symmetry-broken phases in rhombohedral tetralayer graphene have been directly imaged. By probing spin orientation and magnetic anisotropy at ultra-low fields, key energy scales — the spin–orbit coupling and intervalley Hund’s exchange — have been extracted, shedding new light on the phase hierarchy in strongly correlated electron systems.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Overcoming high-voltage limits in all-solid-state batteries with a fluoride-based shielding layer - Nature Energy</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41560-025-01866-x"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41560-025-01866-x</id>
    <summary type="text">Voltage instability of battery materials has hindered the realization of high-voltage all-solid-state batteries (ASSBs). Now, 5 V-class ASSBs are enabled by a fluoride-based shielding layer, LiCl–4Li2TiF6, that combines high oxidative stability and Li+ conductivity. Applied to high-voltage cathodes, the shielding layer mitigates interfacial degradation and enables stable cycling at &amp;gt;5 V, including under high-capacity conditions.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Structural integrity of additively manufactured materials - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-21342-6"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-21342-6</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 34475 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Enhanced penetration and antibacterial efficacy of calcium hydroxide modified with titanium dioxide nanoparticles - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-15023-7"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-15023-7</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 34497 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Terahertz excitation of collective dynamics of polar skyrmions over a broad temperature range - Nature Physics</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03056-8"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03056-8</id>
    <summary type="text">Terahertz control of polar skyrmions—topological textures of electric dipoles—is key for fast optoelectronics. Now, ultrafast excitation of polar skyrmions is achieved across two orders of magnitude of temperature in an oxide heterostructure.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A stable monoclinic variant and resultant robust ferroelectricity in single-crystalline hafnia-based films - Nature Communications</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63907-z"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63907-z</id>
    <summary type="text">The authors observe robust ferroelectricity, characterized by a wake-up-free effect and endurance up to 1012 cycles, in monoclinic Hf0.5Zr0.5O2 single-crystalline films. This ferroelectric behavior originates from a polar monoclinic variant (space group Pc) stabilized by antiphase boundaries.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quantitative and mechanistic insights into proton dynamics for fast energy storage - Nature Materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02366-9"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02366-9</id>
    <summary type="text">Contributions of vehicular and structural proton transport are quantified in phosphoric acid electrolytes, with linking structural diffusion to hydrogen bonds. The derived conductivity model guides electrolyte-conductivity trends and identifies 5.8 M for low-temperature batteries.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>