<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>4thWave AI — Structural Battery Composites (Aggregated)</title>
    <link>https://www.4thwaveai.com</link>
    <description>Aggregated feed generated by 4thWave AI.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Light-powered chip makes AI 100 times more efficient</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</guid>
      <description>Artificial intelligence is consuming enormous amounts of energy, but researchers at the University of Florida have built a chip that could change everything by using light instead of electricity for a core AI function. By etching microscopic lenses directly onto silicon, they’ve enabled laser-powered computations that cut power use dramatically while maintaining near-perfect accuracy.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/instant-convolution-silicon-photonic-chip.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</guid>
      <description>In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/iridium-catalyst.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why recycling ‘dead’ batteries could save billions and slash pollution</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</guid>
      <description>Lithium battery recycling offers a powerful solution to rising demand, with discarded batteries still holding most of their valuable materials. Compared to mining, recycling slashes emissions and resource use while unlocking major economic potential. Yet infrastructure, policy, and technology hurdles must still be overcome.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/ev-battery-technician.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI just found 5 powerful materials that could replace lithium batteries</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</guid>
      <description>AI is helping scientists crack the code on next-gen batteries that could replace lithium-ion tech. By discovering novel porous materials, researchers may have paved the way for more powerful and sustainable energy storage using abundant elements like magnesium.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/ai-robot-battery-tech.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists discover salt that makes batteries last 10x longer</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</guid>
      <description>A team at KAUST has revealed that the short lifespan of aqueous batteries is primarily due to &amp;quot;free water&amp;quot; molecules triggering harmful chemical reactions at the anode. By adding affordable sulfate salts like zinc sulfate, they significantly reduced this issue—boosting battery life over tenfold. The sulfate acts as a “water glue,” stabilizing the water structure and halting the energy-wasting reactions. Not only is this solution simple and cost-effective, but early results suggest it may be a universal fix for various types of metal-anode aqueous batteries.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/aqueous-batteries.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You hear the beep, but can’t find the car: The hidden flaw in electric vehicle safety</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</guid>
      <description>As electric vehicles grow more popular, their warning sounds may not be doing enough to protect pedestrians. A Swedish study shows that these signals are hard to locate, especially when multiple vehicles are involved, leaving people unable to tell where danger is coming from or how many cars are nearby.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/Accoustics-Lab-Laser-Pointer-Electric-Car-Testing.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery could boost solid-state battery performance</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers have discovered that the mixing of small particles between two solid electrolytes can generate an effect called a &amp;apos;space charge layer,&amp;apos; an accumulation of electric charge at the interface between the two materials. The finding could aid the development of batteries with solid electrolytes, called solid-state batteries, for applications including mobile devices and electric vehicles.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening to electrons talk</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers present new experimental and theoretical results for the bound electron g-factor in lithium-like tin which has a much higher nuclear charge than any previous measurement. The experimental accuracy reached a level of 0.5 parts per billion. Using an enhanced interelectronic QED method, the theoretical prediction for the g-factor reached a precision of 6 parts per billion.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EV battery recycling key to future lithium supplies</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</guid>
      <description>Lightweight, powerful lithium-ion batteries are crucial for the transition to electric vehicles, and global demand for lithium is set to grow rapidly over the next 25 years. A new analysis looks at how new mining operations and battery recycling could meet that demand. Recycling could play a big role in easing supply constraints, the researchers found.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric buses struggle in the cold, researchers find</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250528131533.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250528131533.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers have released new insights on a pilot program involving all-electric buses in Ithaca, NY, USA -- with implications for cities, schools and other groups that are considering the electrification of their fleets, as well as operators, policymakers and manufacturers.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally stable β-tungsten for spin–orbit torque magnetic random-access memory - Nature Electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-025-01435-w</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-025-01435-w</guid>
      <description>The insertion of thin cobalt layers increases the thermal stability of β-tungsten. Using this composite as the spin current source in a 64-kb spin–orbit torque magnetic random-access memory array enables back-end-of-line process compatibility and efficient magnetization switching — achieving 1 ns switching, data retention of more than 10 years and 146% tunnelling magnetoresistance.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41928-025-01435-w/MediaObjects/41928_2025_1435_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pipe dream beam coming true - Nature Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02347-y</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02347-y</guid>
      <description>Delayed femtosecond photoemission from a single-walled carbon nanotube enables pulsed electron beams with an unprecedented combination of pulse duration and energy spread.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41563-025-02347-y/MediaObjects/41563_2025_2347_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioelectronic implants built from rolled-up stretchy circuits</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02704-6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02704-6</guid>
      <description>Soft devices made by rolling up rubber-like sheets patterned with 2D electronics can monitor, stimulate and navigate deep tissue in animal models.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.nature.com/lw1200/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02704-6/d41586-025-02704-6_51451436.jpg" type="image/jpeg" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materials advances for distributed environmental sensor networks at scale - Nature Reviews Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-025-00838-7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-025-00838-7</guid>
      <description>Accurate, spatiotemporally resolved monitoring of environments and ecosystems serves as the starting point to both identify and remedy natural or anthropogenic environmental hazards. This Review covers materials science advances supporting a new paradigm in environmental sensing: distributed networks of sensing elements capable of system-level profiling with the possibility of harmless environmental resorption after a predetermined recording period.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41578-025-00838-7/MediaObjects/41578_2025_838_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact-resistant, haze-free, 3D-printable transparent block copolymer resin via photopolymerization-induced microphase separation - NPG Asia Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41427-025-00618-3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41427-025-00618-3</guid>
      <description>We developed impact-resistant, haze-free poly(methyl methacrylate) (PMMA) by photopolymerization-induced microphase separation. Upon irradiation, a polymerization mixture transforms into a transparent monolithic solid. A nanoscopic bicontinuous morphology of glassy PMMA with rubbery and cross-linked polymer domains retains transparency and dimension stability even at high temperatures. 3D printing via direct ink writing demonstrates the potential of the developed material for advanced optical and structural applications.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41427-025-00618-3/MediaObjects/41427_2025_618_Figa_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the influence of coupling agents on the composition of artificial rocks with polymer matrix - Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-18783-4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-18783-4</guid>
      <description>Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 32619 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-18783-4/MediaObjects/41598_2025_18783_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoupled dual-salt electrolyte for practical aqueous zinc batteries - Nature Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01646-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-025-01646-1</guid>
      <description>Aqueous zinc batteries possess advantages in safety, cost and environmental friendliness. To address side reaction, limited cycle life and other challenges, the authors formulate a dual-salt electrolyte that decouples the interfacial electrolyte from the bulk, enabling suppressed hydrogen evolution, fast zinc transport and resilience against low temperature.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41893-025-01646-1/MediaObjects/41893_2025_1646_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting fracture in disordered network materials using the local intelligent stress threshold indicator - Communications Physics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-025-02315-7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-025-02315-7</guid>
      <description>Network glass fracture is a sudden, complex process lacking clear precursors. Here, the authors develop the local intelligent stress threshold indicator (LISTI), a neural network-based tool that predicts nanoscale crack nucleation by correlating local stress thresholds with structural topology, offering a method to identify fracture-prone zones in network glasses.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs42005-025-02315-7/MediaObjects/42005_2025_2315_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>