<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Structural Battery Composites (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://www.4thwaveai.com"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/structural-battery-composites.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:structural-battery-composites</id>
  <updated>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 05:40:45 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>New cooling breakthrough nearly doubles efficiency</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250919085242.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250919085242.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">CHESS thin-film materials nearly double refrigeration efficiency compared to traditional methods. Scalable and versatile, they promise applications from household cooling to space exploration.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Light-powered chip makes AI 100 times more efficient</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Artificial intelligence is consuming enormous amounts of energy, but researchers at the University of Florida have built a chip that could change everything by using light instead of electricity for a core AI function. By etching microscopic lenses directly onto silicon, they’ve enabled laser-powered computations that cut power use dramatically while maintaining near-perfect accuracy.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why recycling ‘dead’ batteries could save billions and slash pollution</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Lithium battery recycling offers a powerful solution to rising demand, with discarded batteries still holding most of their valuable materials. Compared to mining, recycling slashes emissions and resource use while unlocking major economic potential. Yet infrastructure, policy, and technology hurdles must still be overcome.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI just found 5 powerful materials that could replace lithium batteries</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">AI is helping scientists crack the code on next-gen batteries that could replace lithium-ion tech. By discovering novel porous materials, researchers may have paved the way for more powerful and sustainable energy storage using abundant elements like magnesium.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists discover salt that makes batteries last 10x longer</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">A team at KAUST has revealed that the short lifespan of aqueous batteries is primarily due to &amp;quot;free water&amp;quot; molecules triggering harmful chemical reactions at the anode. By adding affordable sulfate salts like zinc sulfate, they significantly reduced this issue—boosting battery life over tenfold. The sulfate acts as a “water glue,” stabilizing the water structure and halting the energy-wasting reactions. Not only is this solution simple and cost-effective, but early results suggest it may be a universal fix for various types of metal-anode aqueous batteries.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You hear the beep, but can’t find the car: The hidden flaw in electric vehicle safety</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">As electric vehicles grow more popular, their warning sounds may not be doing enough to protect pedestrians. A Swedish study shows that these signals are hard to locate, especially when multiple vehicles are involved, leaving people unable to tell where danger is coming from or how many cars are nearby.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Discovery could boost solid-state battery performance</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers have discovered that the mixing of small particles between two solid electrolytes can generate an effect called a &amp;apos;space charge layer,&amp;apos; an accumulation of electric charge at the interface between the two materials. The finding could aid the development of batteries with solid electrolytes, called solid-state batteries, for applications including mobile devices and electric vehicles.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Listening to electrons talk</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers present new experimental and theoretical results for the bound electron g-factor in lithium-like tin which has a much higher nuclear charge than any previous measurement. The experimental accuracy reached a level of 0.5 parts per billion. Using an enhanced interelectronic QED method, the theoretical prediction for the g-factor reached a precision of 6 parts per billion.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EV battery recycling key to future lithium supplies</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Lightweight, powerful lithium-ion batteries are crucial for the transition to electric vehicles, and global demand for lithium is set to grow rapidly over the next 25 years. A new analysis looks at how new mining operations and battery recycling could meet that demand. Recycling could play a big role in easing supply constraints, the researchers found.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Increasing the efficiency of binary organic solar cells through a two-step crystallization process - Nature Energy</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41560-025-01881-y"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41560-025-01881-y</id>
    <summary type="text">Controlling the morphology of the active layer in organic solar cells (OSCs) is challenging. Now, acenaphthene is shown to induce the two-step crystallization of non-fullerene acceptors to achieve a highly oriented arrangement. The resulting improvement in the charge transport properties enables a binary OSC with 21% efficiency and a 83.2% fill factor.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Adsorptive membrane for PFAS removal - Nature Water</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00510-y"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44221-025-00510-y</id>
    <summary type="text">Efficient, low-cost removal of trace per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs) from water is challenging to achieve. Low-pressure adsorptive membranes that are easy to regenerate have great potential for removing trace contaminants such as PFASs from aqueous systems.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Electrostatic-based transfer keeps 2D materials ultra-clean</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02822-1"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02822-1</id>
    <summary type="text">A technique that spontaneously detaches a 2D material from the substrate on which it was grown creates high-quality nanoscale electronic devices.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tunable sensing properties of a Helmholtz resonator array featuring a central defect cell with four lateral ducts - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-20363-5"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-20363-5</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 33316 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Long-term degradation of adsorbed natural gas storage in the MOF Basolite C300 due to Cn≥2 alkanes accumulation - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-10131-w"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-10131-w</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 33054 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Advances in biomonitoring technologies for women’s health - Nature Communications</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63501-3"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-63501-3</id>
    <summary type="text">In global healthcare systems, sex and gender biases have led to a health gap that affects diverse populations of women. This review highlights emerging wearable, biomonitoring, and diagnostic technologies to address this health gap, examines the commercial landscape and barriers to adoption, and discusses opportunities for future innovation.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Exact extraction of stress intensity factors via enriched numerical manifold method with composite patches - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-08168-y"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-08168-y</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 32960 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Surface characterization, wettability and antimicrobial ability of anodic oxide TiO2 layers on Ti45Nb alloy - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-16330-9"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-16330-9</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 32974 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>