<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>4thWave AI — Structural Battery Composites (Aggregated)</title>
    <link>https://4thwave.ai</link>
    <description>Aggregated feed generated by 4thWave AI.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 15:39:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Light-powered chip makes AI 100 times more efficient</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</guid>
      <description>Artificial intelligence is consuming enormous amounts of energy, but researchers at the University of Florida have built a chip that could change everything by using light instead of electricity for a core AI function. By etching microscopic lenses directly onto silicon, they’ve enabled laser-powered computations that cut power use dramatically while maintaining near-perfect accuracy.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/instant-convolution-silicon-photonic-chip.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</guid>
      <description>In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/iridium-catalyst.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why recycling ‘dead’ batteries could save billions and slash pollution</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</guid>
      <description>Lithium battery recycling offers a powerful solution to rising demand, with discarded batteries still holding most of their valuable materials. Compared to mining, recycling slashes emissions and resource use while unlocking major economic potential. Yet infrastructure, policy, and technology hurdles must still be overcome.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/ev-battery-technician.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI just found 5 powerful materials that could replace lithium batteries</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</guid>
      <description>AI is helping scientists crack the code on next-gen batteries that could replace lithium-ion tech. By discovering novel porous materials, researchers may have paved the way for more powerful and sustainable energy storage using abundant elements like magnesium.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/ai-robot-battery-tech.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists discover salt that makes batteries last 10x longer</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</guid>
      <description>A team at KAUST has revealed that the short lifespan of aqueous batteries is primarily due to &amp;quot;free water&amp;quot; molecules triggering harmful chemical reactions at the anode. By adding affordable sulfate salts like zinc sulfate, they significantly reduced this issue—boosting battery life over tenfold. The sulfate acts as a “water glue,” stabilizing the water structure and halting the energy-wasting reactions. Not only is this solution simple and cost-effective, but early results suggest it may be a universal fix for various types of metal-anode aqueous batteries.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/aqueous-batteries.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You hear the beep, but can’t find the car: The hidden flaw in electric vehicle safety</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</guid>
      <description>As electric vehicles grow more popular, their warning sounds may not be doing enough to protect pedestrians. A Swedish study shows that these signals are hard to locate, especially when multiple vehicles are involved, leaving people unable to tell where danger is coming from or how many cars are nearby.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/1920/Accoustics-Lab-Laser-Pointer-Electric-Car-Testing.webp" type="image/webp" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery could boost solid-state battery performance</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers have discovered that the mixing of small particles between two solid electrolytes can generate an effect called a &amp;apos;space charge layer,&amp;apos; an accumulation of electric charge at the interface between the two materials. The finding could aid the development of batteries with solid electrolytes, called solid-state batteries, for applications including mobile devices and electric vehicles.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening to electrons talk</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers present new experimental and theoretical results for the bound electron g-factor in lithium-like tin which has a much higher nuclear charge than any previous measurement. The experimental accuracy reached a level of 0.5 parts per billion. Using an enhanced interelectronic QED method, the theoretical prediction for the g-factor reached a precision of 6 parts per billion.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EV battery recycling key to future lithium supplies</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</guid>
      <description>Lightweight, powerful lithium-ion batteries are crucial for the transition to electric vehicles, and global demand for lithium is set to grow rapidly over the next 25 years. A new analysis looks at how new mining operations and battery recycling could meet that demand. Recycling could play a big role in easing supply constraints, the researchers found.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric buses struggle in the cold, researchers find</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250528131533.htm</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250528131533.htm</guid>
      <description>Researchers have released new insights on a pilot program involving all-electric buses in Ithaca, NY, USA -- with implications for cities, schools and other groups that are considering the electrification of their fleets, as well as operators, policymakers and manufacturers.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-icon.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron at the boundaries - Nature Physics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03041-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03041-1</guid>
      <description>Materials science</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41567-025-03041-1/MediaObjects/41567_2025_3041_Figa_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot off the press - Nature Chemical Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44286-025-00265-z</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s44286-025-00265-z</guid>
      <description>Advancing the production of covalent organic frameworks toward faster and more sustainable routes is crucial to realizing their potential in large-scale applications. Now, a variety of covalent organic framework platelets with high crystallinity can be produced rapidly using a pressure-assisted hot-pressing strategy.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs44286-025-00265-z/MediaObjects/44286_2025_265_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards spin-wave integrated circuits - Nature Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02349-w</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02349-w</guid>
      <description>Borrowing from optical fibre design, ion implantation enables index-contrast guiding of spin waves, opening new opportunities in wave-based computing.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41563-025-02349-w/MediaObjects/41563_2025_2349_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating structurally and functionally programmable hydrogels by biological membrane hybridization - Nature Protocols</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41596-025-01247-4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41596-025-01247-4</guid>
      <description>This protocol describes a versatile strategy to generate structurally and functionally programmable hydrogels by using biological membranes as cross-linkers. This enables properties of tissues like muscle and skin to be mimicked.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41596-025-01247-4/MediaObjects/41596_2025_1247_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskites for next-generation colour conversion displays - Nature Electronics</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-025-01456-5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-025-01456-5</guid>
      <description>This Perspective examines the potential of using perovskite materials as colour conversion layers, providing a framework for the development of RoHS (Restriction of Hazardous Substances)-compliant and colour-filter-free perovskite-based colour conversion displays and exploring the use of perovskite colour conversion layers in the development of augmented reality and virtual reality technologies.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41928-025-01456-5/MediaObjects/41928_2025_1456_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics and photonics-related research and education at POSTECH - Nature Reviews Electrical Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44287-025-00213-2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s44287-025-00213-2</guid>
      <description>Electronics and photonics research at Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH) spans from metasurface flat optical devices to quantum and stretchable electronics. In this Viewpoint, five professors discuss how&amp;nbsp;POSTECH, with strong industry ties and interdisciplinary collaborations, aims to redefine nanoscale electronic and photonic materials and devices, quantum electronics and photonics, future information technology and computing.</description>
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The van der Waals MoSi2N4 materials family - Nature Reviews Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-025-00832-z</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41578-025-00832-z</guid>
      <description>The van der Waals MA2Z4 materials are a rapidly growing class of 2D materials with diverse electronic phases. This Review explores the structure,&amp;nbsp;synthesis, properties and diverse applications of the emerging MA2Z4 family, highlighting their potential across electronics, catalysis and energy storage.</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41578-025-00832-z/MediaObjects/41578_2025_832_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrothermal discharge by exploding of copper wires with different diameters - Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-11130-7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-11130-7</guid>
      <description>Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 32416 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</description>
      <enclosure url="https://media.springernature.com/m685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-025-11130-7/MediaObjects/41598_2025_11130_Fig1_HTML.png" type="image/png" />
      <category>structural-battery-composites</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>