<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Structural Battery Composites (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://4thwave.ai"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/structural-battery-composites.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:structural-battery-composites</id>
  <updated>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:30:59 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Light-powered chip makes AI 100 times more efficient</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/09/250908175458.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Artificial intelligence is consuming enormous amounts of energy, but researchers at the University of Florida have built a chip that could change everything by using light instead of electricity for a core AI function. By etching microscopic lenses directly onto silicon, they’ve enabled laser-powered computations that cut power use dramatically while maintaining near-perfect accuracy.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A tiny chip may have solved one of clean energy’s biggest problems</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250828060040.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">In just one afternoon, scientists used a nanoparticle “megalibrary” to find a catalyst that matches or exceeds iridium’s performance in hydrogen fuel production, at a fraction of the cost.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why recycling ‘dead’ batteries could save billions and slash pollution</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250818103002.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Lithium battery recycling offers a powerful solution to rising demand, with discarded batteries still holding most of their valuable materials. Compared to mining, recycling slashes emissions and resource use while unlocking major economic potential. Yet infrastructure, policy, and technology hurdles must still be overcome.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI just found 5 powerful materials that could replace lithium batteries</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/08/250802022915.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">AI is helping scientists crack the code on next-gen batteries that could replace lithium-ion tech. By discovering novel porous materials, researchers may have paved the way for more powerful and sustainable energy storage using abundant elements like magnesium.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scientists discover salt that makes batteries last 10x longer</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/07/250726234421.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">A team at KAUST has revealed that the short lifespan of aqueous batteries is primarily due to &amp;quot;free water&amp;quot; molecules triggering harmful chemical reactions at the anode. By adding affordable sulfate salts like zinc sulfate, they significantly reduced this issue—boosting battery life over tenfold. The sulfate acts as a “water glue,” stabilizing the water structure and halting the energy-wasting reactions. Not only is this solution simple and cost-effective, but early results suggest it may be a universal fix for various types of metal-anode aqueous batteries.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You hear the beep, but can’t find the car: The hidden flaw in electric vehicle safety</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250618094455.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">As electric vehicles grow more popular, their warning sounds may not be doing enough to protect pedestrians. A Swedish study shows that these signals are hard to locate, especially when multiple vehicles are involved, leaving people unable to tell where danger is coming from or how many cars are nearby.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Discovery could boost solid-state battery performance</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/06/250602154903.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers have discovered that the mixing of small particles between two solid electrolytes can generate an effect called a &amp;apos;space charge layer,&amp;apos; an accumulation of electric charge at the interface between the two materials. The finding could aid the development of batteries with solid electrolytes, called solid-state batteries, for applications including mobile devices and electric vehicles.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Listening to electrons talk</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529155435.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers present new experimental and theoretical results for the bound electron g-factor in lithium-like tin which has a much higher nuclear charge than any previous measurement. The experimental accuracy reached a level of 0.5 parts per billion. Using an enhanced interelectronic QED method, the theoretical prediction for the g-factor reached a precision of 6 parts per billion.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EV battery recycling key to future lithium supplies</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250529124724.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Lightweight, powerful lithium-ion batteries are crucial for the transition to electric vehicles, and global demand for lithium is set to grow rapidly over the next 25 years. A new analysis looks at how new mining operations and battery recycling could meet that demand. Recycling could play a big role in easing supply constraints, the researchers found.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Electric buses struggle in the cold, researchers find</title>
    <link href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250528131533.htm"/>
    <id>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/05/250528131533.htm</id>
    <summary type="text">Researchers have released new insights on a pilot program involving all-electric buses in Ithaca, NY, USA -- with implications for cities, schools and other groups that are considering the electrification of their fleets, as well as operators, policymakers and manufacturers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Salt turns ice into a powerful flexoelectric material - Nature Materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02328-1"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02328-1</id>
    <summary type="text">The brine network in common sea ice boosts its flexoelectric response by three orders of magnitude, matching high-quality piezoelectrics and pointing to cost-effective energy harvesters for cold environments.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Terahertz light confined to the nanoscale with hafnium dichalcogenides - Nature Materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02353-0"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02353-0</id>
    <summary type="text">Terahertz technology has the potential to push the speed limit of future opto-electronic applications, but the large free-space wavelength of terahertz light hinders nanoscale device implementation. Now, the confinement of terahertz light to the nanometre scale is demonstrated using phonon polaritons in hafnium-based van der Waals crystals.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Boron at the boundaries - Nature Physics</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03041-1"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41567-025-03041-1</id>
    <summary type="text">Materials science</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Streaming flexoelectricity in saline ice - Nature Materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02332-5"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-025-02332-5</id>
    <summary type="text">By doping ice with NaCl, it is shown that a flexoelectric coefficient of up to 10 μC m−1 is generated, enabling effective piezoelectric coefficients that are comparable to those of ceramics. This arises from the streaming current of quasi-liquid flow through grain boundaries from one side of the sample to the other.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Revealing nanoscale plasticity of metallic nanosponges with correlative and scale-bridging 3D microscopy and modelling - Communications Materials</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-025-00914-z"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s43246-025-00914-z</id>
    <summary type="text">The mechanical properties of nanoporous gold are tied to their topology and surface morphology. Here, a correlative and scale-bridging approach, combining non-destructive 3D tomography, mechanical testing and experimentally-informed modelling, reveals the origins of the size dependent deformation mechanisms.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amorphous indium tin oxide transistors for power amplification above 10 GHz - Nature Electronics</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-025-01447-6"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-025-01447-6</id>
    <summary type="text">The electrical and thermal transport properties of amorphous indium tin oxide can be enhanced by using a silicon carbide substrate, leading to indium tin oxide power amplifiers with an output power density of 0.69 W mm−1 and a power-added efficiency of 24.1% at 12 GHz.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Perovskite-based multi-junction solar cells - Nature Reviews Clean Technology</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44359-025-00103-8"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s44359-025-00103-8</id>
    <summary type="text">Multi-junction solar cells can provide a way to increase the efficiency of solar cells beyond the theoretical efficiency limits of single-junction devices. This Review explores the design and performance of multi-junction devices that use perovskite materials for the two wide bandgap middle and top layers.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Modeling graphene oxide decorated with FeO, SO and NO - Scientific Reports</title>
    <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-18685-5"/>
    <id>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-18685-5</id>
    <summary type="text">Scientific Reports volume 15 , Article number: 32538 ( 2025 ) Cite this article</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>