<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Tech Leaders (Spotlights)</title>
  <link href="https://4thwave.ai"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/tech-leaders.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:tech-leaders</id>
  <updated>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:54:10 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Amazon in the community: Service, community, and commitment at HQ2</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/community/amazon-arlington-virginia-news"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/community/amazon-arlington-virginia-news</id>
    <summary type="text">Learn how we invest in the community, help power the local economy, and support our employees in Arlington, Virginia.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 22:07:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The AI Makers: NVIDIA Partners in UK Advance Physical and Agentic AI, Robotics, Life Sciences and More</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-partner-ecosystem-ai-makers/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-partner-ecosystem-ai-makers/</id>
    <summary type="text">During NVIDIA founder and CEO Jensen Huang’s visit to the U.K. this week, NVIDIA highlighted how it is working with a broad ecosystem of AI makers across the nation on applications in physical and agentic AI, robotics and healthcare.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:30:16 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Microsoft leads shift beyond data unification to organization, delivering next-gen AI readiness with new Microsoft Fabric capabilities - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/16/microsoft-leads-shift-beyond-data-unification-to-organization-delivering-next-gen-ai-readiness-with-new-microsoft-fabric-capabilities/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/16/microsoft-leads-shift-beyond-data-unification-to-organization-delivering-next-gen-ai-readiness-with-new-microsoft-fabric-capabilities/</id>
    <summary type="text">We’re in a hinge moment for AI. The experiments are over and the real work has begun. Centralizing data, once the finish line, is now the starting point. The definition of “AI readiness” is evolving as increasingly sophisticated agents demand rich, contextualized data grounded in business operations to deliver meaningful results. What sets leaders apart...</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:00:04 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reaching Across the Isles: UK-LLM Brings AI to UK Languages With NVIDIA Nemotron</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-llm-nemotron/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/uk-llm-nemotron/</id>
    <summary type="text">Trained on the Isambard-AI supercomputer, UK-LLM enables AI reasoning for Welsh and other UK languages for public services.</summary>
    <updated>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 01:00:21 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A joint statement from Microsoft and OpenAI - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/11/a-joint-statement-from-microsoft-and-openai/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/11/a-joint-statement-from-microsoft-and-openai/</id>
    <summary type="text">Microsoft and OpenAI have signed a non-binding memorandum of understanding (MOU) for the next phase of our partnership. We are actively working to finalize contractual terms in a definitive agreement. Together, we remain focused on delivering the best AI tools for everyone, grounded in our shared commitment to safety.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:30:02 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Five Years On, Reels Reigns as India&#x27;s Top Short-Form Video Platform</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/five-years-on-reels-reigns-as-indias-top-short-form-video-platform/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/five-years-on-reels-reigns-as-indias-top-short-form-video-platform/</id>
    <summary type="text">Findings from a new Meta-commissioned IPSOS study show that Reels across our platforms is India’s top driver of daily video consumption ahead of other surveyed platforms.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 08:01:55 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Flexible work update - The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/09/flexible-work-update/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2025/09/09/flexible-work-update/</id>
    <summary type="text">Amy Coleman, Executive Vice President and Chief People Officer, shared the below communication with Microsoft employees this morning. How we work has forever changed. I remember starting at Microsoft in the late ‘90s, always in the office, no laptops, and primarily working with the people right down the hall. As technology evolved and our business expanded, we became...</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:05:44 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA Partners With AI Infrastructure Ecosystem to Unveil Reference Design for Giga-Scale AI Factories</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/ai-factories-reference-design/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/ai-factories-reference-design/</id>
    <summary type="text">At this week’s AI Infrastructure Summit in Silicon Valley, NVIDIA’s VP of Accelerated Computing Ian Buck unveiled a bold new vision: the transformation of traditional data centers into fully integrated AI factories. As part of this initiative, NVIDIA is developing reference designs to be shared with partners and enterprises worldwide — offering an NVIDIA Omniverse  Read Article</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:00:29 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Attach Text to Your Threads Posts and Share Longer Perspectives</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/attach-text-threads-posts-share-longer-perspectives/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/attach-text-threads-posts-share-longer-perspectives/</id>
    <summary type="text">We&#x27;re rolling out a way for you to attach up to 10,000 characters of text to a Threads post.</summary>
    <updated>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:00:51 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Instagram Launches A Microdrama Series To Encourage Gen Z To Take Creative Chances</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/instagram-launches-a-microdrama-series-to-encourage-gen-z-to-take-creative-chances/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/09/instagram-launches-a-microdrama-series-to-encourage-gen-z-to-take-creative-chances/</id>
    <summary type="text">Today, Instagram released a microdrama series in India to inspire Gen Z to take creative risks and bring them together. Titled ‘Party of Two’, the series follows Instagram’s ‘Anyway’ campaign from this year.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:05:56 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meta’s Kansas City Data Center and Upcoming AI-Optimized Data Centers</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/08/metas-kansas-city-data-center/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/08/metas-kansas-city-data-center/</id>
    <summary type="text">Our Kansas City data center is now operational, representing a $1 billion investment in Missouri and in our global infrastructure that brings our technologies to billions of people worldwide.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:00:26 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Instagram Features to Help You Connect</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/08/new-instagram-features-help-you-connect/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/08/new-instagram-features-help-you-connect/</id>
    <summary type="text">We’re launching features that make it easier to connect with your friends on Instagram.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:00:28 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Personal Superintelligence for Everyone</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/07/personal-superintelligence-for-everyone/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/07/personal-superintelligence-for-everyone/</id>
    <summary type="text">Today, Meta Founder &amp; CEO Mark Zuckerberg shared his vision to bring personal superintelligence to everyone.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 13:01:48 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Score big with Prime for Young Adults—Amazon’s discounted Prime membership</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-prime-for-young-adults"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-prime-for-young-adults</id>
    <summary type="text">Learn about the extraordinary value of the go-to Prime membership for 18-to-24-year-olds. Eligible new members can try it for six months for $0 and earn 5% cash back.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 04:30:11 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>You Can Now Edit Videos With Meta AI</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/06/edit-videos-with-meta-ai/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/06/edit-videos-with-meta-ai/</id>
    <summary type="text">We’re launching a generative AI video editing feature across the Meta AI app, the Meta.AI website and the Edits app to help you bring your creative ideas to life.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:00:14 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kuiper mission updates: Kuiper constellation grows to more than 100 satellites</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation-at-amazon/project-kuiper-satellite-rocket-launch-progress-updates"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/innovation-at-amazon/project-kuiper-satellite-rocket-launch-progress-updates</id>
    <summary type="text">Follow along for updates as Project Kuiper launches more than 80 missions to deploy our initial low Earth orbit satellite internet constellation.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:30:15 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaQubit tackles one of quantum computing’s biggest challenges</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaqubit-tackles-one-of-quantum-computings-biggest-challenges/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaqubit-tackles-one-of-quantum-computings-biggest-challenges/</id>
    <summary type="text">AlphaQubit is an AI-based decoder that identifies quantum computing errors with state-of-the-art accuracy.</summary>
    <updated>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Is a Prime membership worth it? The short answer is yes.</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-prime-membership-worth-it"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-prime-membership-worth-it</id>
    <summary type="text">Here are all the perks and benefits that make a Prime membership well worth the cost.</summary>
    <updated>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 12:45:49 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>7 Prime benefits that will save you money</title>
    <link href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/prime-benefits-that-will-save-you-money"/>
    <id>https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/prime-benefits-that-will-save-you-money</id>
    <summary type="text">It’s not just about free shipping and Prime Video. Prime keeps money back in your pocket.</summary>
    <updated>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 13:00:00 +0000</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA and United Kingdom Build Nation’s AI Infrastructure and Ecosystem to Fuel Innovation, Economic Growth and Jobs</title>
    <link href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-and-united-kingdom-build-nations-ai-infrastructure-and-ecosystem-to-fuel-innovation-economic-growth-and-jobs"/>
    <id>https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-and-united-kingdom-build-nations-ai-infrastructure-and-ecosystem-to-fuel-innovation-economic-growth-and-jobs</id>
    <summary type="text">NVIDIA today announced that it is investing in accelerating the AI industrial revolution in the United Kingdom, working with partners including CoreWeave, Microsoft and Nscale to build the nation’s next generation of AI infrastructure.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA Unveils Rubin CPX: A New Class of GPU Designed for Massive-Context Inference</title>
    <link href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-unveils-rubin-cpx-a-new-class-of-gpu-designed-for-massive-context-inference"/>
    <id>https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-unveils-rubin-cpx-a-new-class-of-gpu-designed-for-massive-context-inference</id>
    <summary type="text">NVIDIA® today announced NVIDIA Rubin CPX, a new class of GPU purpose-built for massive-context processing. This enables AI systems to handle million-token software coding and generative video with groundbreaking speed and efficiency.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NVIDIA Announces Financial Results for Second Quarter Fiscal 2026</title>
    <link href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-financial-results-for-second-quarter-fiscal-2026"/>
    <id>https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-announces-financial-results-for-second-quarter-fiscal-2026</id>
    <summary type="text">NVIDIA (NASDAQ: NVDA) today reported revenue for the second quarter ended July 27, 2025, of $46.7 billion, up 6% from the previous quarter and up 56% from a year ago. NVIDIA’s Blackwell Data Center revenue grew 17% sequentially.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Generative AI Archives</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/generative-ai/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/generative-ai/</id>
    <summary type="text">The U.K. is driving investments in sovereign AI, using the technology to advance industries like manufacturing, life sciences… Read Article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Corporate Archives</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/corporate/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/corporate/</id>
    <summary type="text">NVIDIA Corporate Blog Post Archive</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Data Center Archives</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/enterprise/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/enterprise/</id>
    <summary type="text">The U.K. is driving investments in sovereign AI, using the technology to advance industries like manufacturing, life sciences… Read Article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Driving Archives</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/auto/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/auto/</id>
    <summary type="text">At this week’s IAA Mobility conference in Munich, NVIDIA Vice President of Automotive Ali Kani outlined how cloud-to-car… Read Article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gaming Archives</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/gaming/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/category/gaming/</id>
    <summary type="text">GeForce NOW Blackwell RTX 5080-class SuperPODs are now rolling out, unlocking a new level of ultra high-performance, cinematic… Read Article</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/</id>
    <summary type="text">Discover our latest AI breakthroughs, projects, and updates.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaGenome: AI for better understanding the genome</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphagenome-ai-for-better-understanding-the-genome/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphagenome-ai-for-better-understanding-the-genome/</id>
    <summary type="text">Introducing a new, unifying DNA sequence model that advances regulatory variant-effect prediction and promises to shed new light on genome function — now available via API.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A catalogue of genetic mutations to help pinpoint the cause of diseases</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/a-catalogue-of-genetic-mutations-to-help-pinpoint-the-cause-of-diseases/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/a-catalogue-of-genetic-mutations-to-help-pinpoint-the-cause-of-diseases/</id>
    <summary type="text">New AI tool classifies the effects of 71 million ‘missense’ mutations 
Uncovering the root causes of disease is one of the greatest challenges in human genetics. With millions of possible...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaProteo generates novel proteins for biology and health research</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaproteo-generates-novel-proteins-for-biology-and-health-research/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaproteo-generates-novel-proteins-for-biology-and-health-research/</id>
    <summary type="text">New AI system designs proteins that successfully bind to target molecules, with potential for advancing drug design, disease understanding and more.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AlphaEvolve: A Gemini-powered coding agent for designing advanced algorithms</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaevolve-a-gemini-powered-coding-agent-for-designing-advanced-algorithms/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/alphaevolve-a-gemini-powered-coding-agent-for-designing-advanced-algorithms/</id>
    <summary type="text">New AI agent evolves algorithms for math and practical applications in computing by combining the creativity of large language models with automated evaluators</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AI achieves silver-medal standard solving International Mathematical Olympiad problems</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/ai-solves-imo-problems-at-silver-medal-level/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/ai-solves-imo-problems-at-silver-medal-level/</id>
    <summary type="text">Breakthrough models AlphaProof and AlphaGeometry 2 solve advanced reasoning problems in mathematics</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Millions of new materials discovered with deep learning</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/millions-of-new-materials-discovered-with-deep-learning/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/millions-of-new-materials-discovered-with-deep-learning/</id>
    <summary type="text">We share the discovery of 2.2 million new crystals  –  equivalent to nearly 800 years’ worth of knowledge. We introduce Graph Networks for Materials Exploration (GNoME), our new deep learning tool...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Accelerating fusion science through learned plasma control</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/accelerating-fusion-science-through-learned-plasma-control/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/accelerating-fusion-science-through-learned-plasma-control/</id>
    <summary type="text">Successfully controlling the nuclear fusion plasma in a tokamak with deep reinforcement learning</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Genie 3: A New Frontier for World Models</title>
    <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-3-a-new-frontier-for-world-models/"/>
    <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-3-a-new-frontier-for-world-models/</id>
    <summary type="text">Today we are announcing Genie 3, a general purpose world model that can generate an unprecedented diversity of interactive environments. Given a text prompt, Genie 3 can generate dynamic worlds...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Keyword</title>
    <link href="https://blog.google/"/>
    <id>https://blog.google/</id>
    <summary type="text">Get the latest news and stories about Google products, technology and innovation on the Keyword, Google&#x27;s official blog.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Android</title>
    <link href="https://blog.google/products/android/"/>
    <id>https://blog.google/products/android/</id>
    <summary type="text">Read the latest news and updates about Android, the world&#x27;s most popular mobile platform.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Google Chrome</title>
    <link href="https://blog.google/products/chrome/"/>
    <id>https://blog.google/products/chrome/</id>
    <summary type="text">Read the latest news and updates about Chrome, Google&#x27;s fast, free web browser for your computer, phone, and tablet.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chromebook</title>
    <link href="https://blog.google/products/chromebooks/"/>
    <id>https://blog.google/products/chromebooks/</id>
    <summary type="text">Read the latest news and updates about Chromebooks, the fast and easy to use laptop that helps you enjoy your favorite apps.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Google Play</title>
    <link href="https://blog.google/products/google-play/"/>
    <id>https://blog.google/products/google-play/</id>
    <summary type="text">Read the latest news and updates about Google Play, where you can enjoy your favorite music, movies, books and apps on your Android device, or on the web.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wear OS</title>
    <link href="https://blog.google/products/wear-os/"/>
    <id>https://blog.google/products/wear-os/</id>
    <summary type="text">Read the latest about Wear OS by Google — smartwatches that let you track fitness, read messages and get help from Google Assistant.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jessica Hawk, Author at The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/jessiahawk/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/jessiahawk/</id>
    <summary type="text">Sep 16, 2025 | Jessica Hawk - Corporate Vice President, Data, AI, and Digital Applications, Product Marketing</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Microsoft Corporate Blogs, Author at The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/cdemaria/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/cdemaria/</id>
    <summary type="text">Sep 11, 2025 | Microsoft Corporate Blogs</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amy Coleman, Author at The Official Microsoft Blog</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/acoleman/"/>
    <id>https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/author/acoleman/</id>
    <summary type="text">Sep 9, 2025 | Amy Coleman - Executive Vice President, Chief People Officer</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How the mind-splitting world of Severance comes together on Mac</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/03/how-the-mind-splitting-world-of-severance-comes-together-on-mac/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/03/how-the-mind-splitting-world-of-severance-comes-together-on-mac/</id>
    <summary type="text">How Geoff Richman, lead editor on the Apple Original, “Severance,” created the frenetic world of the hit show’s season two finale.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet four of this year’s Swift Student Challenge winners</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/05/meet-four-of-this-years-swift-student-challenge-winners/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/05/meet-four-of-this-years-swift-student-challenge-winners/</id>
    <summary type="text">Meet Taiki Hamamoto, Marina Lee, Luciana Ortiz Nolasco, and Nahom Worku, four winners of Apple’s 2025 Swift Student Challenge.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet four emerging filmmakers bending cultural and creative lines with iPhone 16 Pro Max</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/04/meet-four-emerging-filmmakers-bending-cultural-and-creative-lines-with-iphone-16-pro-max/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/04/meet-four-emerging-filmmakers-bending-cultural-and-creative-lines-with-iphone-16-pro-max/</id>
    <summary type="text">From a horror-comedy in Tamil to a magical romance in Malayalam, MAMI Select filmmakers are redefining cinema with iPhone 16 Pro Max.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Capturing paradise: Karston Tannis re-creates island vibes with iPhone 16 Pro Max</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/02/capturing-paradise-karston-tannis-re-creates-island-vibes-with-iphone-16-pro-max/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/02/capturing-paradise-karston-tannis-re-creates-island-vibes-with-iphone-16-pro-max/</id>
    <summary type="text">Captured on iPhone 16 Pro Max, a recent shoot by photographer Karston Tannis showcased the vibrancy of the African diaspora.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Newsroom</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/</id>
    <summary type="text">The official source for news about Apple, from Apple. Read press releases, get updates, watch video and download images.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Services - Newsroom</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/apple-services/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/apple-services/</id>
    <summary type="text">The source for news about Apple Services. Get updates on the latest Apple Arcade games, Apple Originals on TV+, Podcasts, Books, and more from Apple Newsroom.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apple Stories - Newsroom</title>
    <link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/apple-stories/"/>
    <id>https://www.apple.com/newsroom/apple-stories/</id>
    <summary type="text">Discover more stories from Apple Newsroom that showcase the creators, developers, and innovators leaving the world better than they found it.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Newsroom | Meta Newsroom</title>
    <link href="https://about.fb.com/news/"/>
    <id>https://about.fb.com/news/</id>
    <summary type="text">View the latest news, announcements and media resources from Meta.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Submit a Media Inquiry | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/media-inquiries"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news/media-inquiries</id>
    <summary type="text">If you’re a member of the press, please contact us at media@blueorigin.com with your inquiry and deadline.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gallery | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/gallery"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news/gallery</id>
    <summary type="text">Images available for download. Please credit Blue Origin.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Shepard NS-35 Mission Updates | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/new-shepard-ns-35-mission"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news/new-shepard-ns-35-mission</id>
    <summary type="text">New Shepard NS-35 is targeting liftoff on Thursday, Sept. 18. The uncrewed payload mission will fly more than 40 scientific and research payloads to space.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blue Alchemist Hits Major Milestone Toward Permanent and Sustainable Lunar Infrastructure | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/blue-alchemist-hits-major-milestone-toward-permanent-sustainable-lunar-infrastructure"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news/blue-alchemist-hits-major-milestone-toward-permanent-sustainable-lunar-infrastructure</id>
    <summary type="text">Blue Origin&#x27;s pioneering in-space resource utilization system, Blue Alchemist, has successfully completed its Critical Design Review, marking a transformative milestone toward humanity&#x27;s permanent expansion beyond Earth.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Mission: Blue Origin’s Mars Telecommunications Orbiter | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/blue-origin-mars-telecommunications-orbiter"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news/blue-origin-mars-telecommunications-orbiter</id>
    <summary type="text">Built upon our existing and affordable Blue Ring platform, our Mars Telecommunications Orbiter is ready to support NASA’s Mars mission in 2028.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blue Origin’s New Shepard Completes 34th Mission to Space | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news/new-shepard-ns-34-mission"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news/new-shepard-ns-34-mission</id>
    <summary type="text">Blue Origin successfully completed its 14th human spaceflight and the 34th flight for the New Shepard program.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>News | Blue Origin</title>
    <link href="https://www.blueorigin.com/news"/>
    <id>https://www.blueorigin.com/news</id>
    <summary type="text">The Latest from Blue</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>