<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Videos (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://www.4thwaveai.com"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/videos.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:videos</id>
  <updated>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:21:26 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA JPL Shakes Things Up Testing Future Commercial Lunar Spacecraft</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-jpl-shakes-things-up-testing-future-commercial-lunar-spacecraft/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-jpl-shakes-things-up-testing-future-commercial-lunar-spacecraft/</id>
    <summary type="text">As Firefly Aerospace prepares to follow its successful soft landing on the Moon, an engineering model for its next lander is being put through its paces.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One of NASA’s Key Cameras Orbiting Mars Takes 100,000th Image</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/one-of-nasas-key-cameras-orbiting-mars-takes-100000th-image/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/one-of-nasas-key-cameras-orbiting-mars-takes-100000th-image/</id>
    <summary type="text">Mesas and dunes stand out in the view snapped by HiRISE, one of the imagers aboard the agency’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA JPL Unveils Rover Operations Center for Moon, Mars Missions</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-jpl-unveils-rover-operations-center-for-moon-mars-missions/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-jpl-unveils-rover-operations-center-for-moon-mars-missions/</id>
    <summary type="text">The center leverages AI along with JPL’s unique infrastructure, unrivaled tools, and years of operations expertise to support industry partners developing future planetary surface missions.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New NASA Sensor Goes Hunting for Critical Minerals</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/new-nasa-sensor-goes-hunting-for-critical-minerals/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/new-nasa-sensor-goes-hunting-for-critical-minerals/</id>
    <summary type="text">Called AVIRIS-5, it’s the latest in a long line of sensors pioneered by NASA JPL to survey Earth, the Moon, and other worlds.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>November 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/12/5/november-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/12/5/november-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">Throughout November, the Terran R program made key advancements across design, build, test, and launch operations.   Design  As the program continues to mature, we are releasing larger groups of parts through our design sprints. In November, we released 1,602 parts, unlocking downstream manufacturin</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>October 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/11/10/october-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/11/10/october-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">As Terran R development continues to advance, we’re excited to share updates from October across design, build, test, and launch.   Design  This month, the team completed 11 component-level critical design reviews. Significant focus was placed on second stage fluids components, and the team successf</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/10/13/september-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/10/13/september-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">The Terran R program continues to build momentum, and September delivered meaningful progress across design, manufacturing, testing, and launch.   Design  September marked steady progress in design maturity, with the completion of 19 component-level critical design reviews, largely focused on the se</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>