<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Videos (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://www.4thwaveai.com"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/videos.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:videos</id>
  <updated>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:35:10 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA’s SPHEREx Observatory Completes First Cosmic Map Like No Other</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasas-spherex-observatory-completes-first-cosmic-map-like-no-other/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasas-spherex-observatory-completes-first-cosmic-map-like-no-other/</id>
    <summary type="text">The telescope will help scientists answer big-picture questions about everything from water deposits in the Milky Way to what happened in the first second after the big bang.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA’s Perseverance Mars Rover Ready to Roll for Miles in Years Ahead</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasas-perseverance-mars-rover-ready-to-roll-for-miles-in-years-ahead/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasas-perseverance-mars-rover-ready-to-roll-for-miles-in-years-ahead/</id>
    <summary type="text">The rover has been acing a long-term series of durability tests, making the most of its enhanced navigation capabilities, and ferreting out new findings about Mars’ geologic past.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NASA JPL Shakes Things Up Testing Future Commercial Lunar Spacecraft</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-jpl-shakes-things-up-testing-future-commercial-lunar-spacecraft/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/nasa-jpl-shakes-things-up-testing-future-commercial-lunar-spacecraft/</id>
    <summary type="text">As Firefly Aerospace prepares to follow its successful soft landing on the Moon, an engineering model for its next lander is being put through its paces.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One of NASA’s Key Cameras Orbiting Mars Takes 100,000th Image</title>
    <link href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/one-of-nasas-key-cameras-orbiting-mars-takes-100000th-image/"/>
    <id>https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/one-of-nasas-key-cameras-orbiting-mars-takes-100000th-image/</id>
    <summary type="text">Mesas and dunes stand out in the view snapped by HiRISE, one of the imagers aboard the agency’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>December 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2026/1/12/december-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2026/1/12/december-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">As we start the new year, here’s a look at key Terran R program milestones from December 2025.&amp;nbsp;   Design  This month, the team released 1,526 flight parts and the integrated thrust structure fluids assembly, unlocking downstream manufacturing and keeping the integration schedule moving at p</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>November 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/12/5/november-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/12/5/november-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">Throughout November, the Terran R program made key advancements across design, build, test, and launch operations.   Design  As the program continues to mature, we are releasing larger groups of parts through our design sprints. In November, we released 1,602 parts, unlocking downstream manufacturin</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>October 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/11/10/october-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/11/10/october-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">As Terran R development continues to advance, we’re excited to share updates from October across design, build, test, and launch.   Design  This month, the team completed 11 component-level critical design reviews. Significant focus was placed on second stage fluids components, and the team successf</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>