<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>4thWave AI — Videos (Aggregated)</title>
  <link href="https://www.4thwaveai.com"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://4thwaveai-feeds.github.io/4thwaveai-feeds/feeds/videos.atom.xml"/>
  <id>urn:4thwaveai-feeds:videos</id>
  <updated>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 20:35:03 +0000</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>August 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/9/8/august-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/9/8/august-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">Throughout August, the Terran R program continued to make measurable progress toward first launch, delivering on critical program milestones.   Design  This month, the team completed 18 component-level Critical Design Reviews (CDRs), most of which focused on the second stage engine and fluids system</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>July 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/8/7/july-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/8/7/july-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">As development of Terran R continues to accelerate, July marked another month of meaningful progress across design, manufacturing, testing, and launch operations.   Design  In July, the team successfully completed 28 additional component-level Critical Design Reviews (CDRs). Notably, 351 thrust stru</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>June 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/7/8/june-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/7/8/june-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">As the Terran R program continues to advance, we’re highlighting some of the latest milestones across design, build, test, and launch.   Design&amp;nbsp;  Throughout June, the team completed 12 additional component-level critical design reviews (CDRs), covering a range of hardware from trays and flu</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>May 2025 Company Update</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/6/6/may-2025-company-update"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/press-release/2025/6/6/may-2025-company-update</id>
    <summary type="text">As we close out another month of Terran R development, we’re sharing a look at recent progress across design, build, test, and launch.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;   Design &amp;nbsp; In May, we completed an additional 17 component-level critical design reviews (CDR). At this stage of the program, many of th</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Updates</title>
    <link href="https://www.relativityspace.com/news"/>
    <id>https://www.relativityspace.com/news</id>
    <summary type="text">Learn about Terran R’s progress towards reusability.</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>